<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rdf:RDF
	xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
>
<channel rdf:about="http://india.linuxchix.org/planet">
	<title>Planet LinuxChix India</title>
	<link>http://india.linuxchix.org/planet</link>
	<description>Planet LinuxChix India - http://india.linuxchix.org/planet</description>

	<items>
		<rdf:Seq>
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:f7aa02bd93da6a4c62747fdddc280513" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://barkha.in/blog/?p=164" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:2928117ef2887e124743b7bf07fd785e" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:e4ae29bcb8cd3c4ca4aa106d812c8e6c" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3835450307118836937.post-890022578992145982" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://archu.wordpress.com/?p=803" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:824ec2573e073b517a6b354446028b7f" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:lj:livejournal.com:atom1:kadambarid:82520" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://archu.wordpress.com/?p=792" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://archu.wordpress.com/?p=786" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://archu.wordpress.com/?p=781" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://archu.wordpress.com/?p=774" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://archu.wordpress.com/?p=771" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://archu.wordpress.com/?p=765" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3835450307118836937.post-8156460927610810513" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://amrita.dgplug.org/?p=57" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://archu.wordpress.com/?p=762" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://barkha.in/blog/?p=160" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://barkha.in/blog/2011/08/17/test-post-from-the-iphone-app/" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://barkha.in/blog/?p=155" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://opensourcebuzz.technetra.com/?p=434" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://archu.wordpress.com/?p=758" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:584d88d40ebfb33b1ea1295b8687356f" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://barkha.in/blog/?p=151" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:4dd38721281663fbbd4ea514c80ae69e" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://opensourcebuzz.technetra.com/?p=432" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:84590c44fbcb98115873bd03ecbf0ccd" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://netra.wordpress.com/?p=420" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:b584848b96a6a38f2e3e3c76b55eaab8" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:4bcc1f64fdc58e0dd2dadc25a13431c1" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:11c2984e73e08452c926a512fb3ec38a" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:95fac4245258de0bbfe9bb2906a88991" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3835450307118836937.post-5359240188621531554" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:bd68364f1eca2977a3342b99d8adb5d0" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:d4a7df9f8f23e154aeb4110c4d81277b" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://barkha.in/blog/?p=145" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:6eb9b80ff562205eeb7377fba2a483d9" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:lj:livejournal.com:atom1:kadambarid:81865" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://archu.wordpress.com/2010/12/21/cool-cooler-coldest-not-liking-this/" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:e0c305c23f3e311c153e75023786dc32" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://barkha.in/blog/?p=142" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4752247183054428289.post-3011788326889941224" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://netra.wordpress.com/?p=374" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://opensourcebuzz.technetra.com/?p=429" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:e7c63da8aaf7aac526d74f2fb069f230" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:a0c2433f0e14eeab8432f21970683c62" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:439a9a60e9c948c542c06425a5d0d734" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:cec481b5610dae08a4f908177f3109c4" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:002216bc84d8cb91c3ec3d575cb49573" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:6b413b825604052a6b0557e32eea6d1e" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:821e032eba8eb0c6056d3ff0421ff3b2" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:5ec8805a2a1fc20c5c3ff35979412bd7" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4752247183054428289.post-7644676723622088348" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4752247183054428289.post-2557162170420241408" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://barkha.in/blog/?p=141" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:c05cf2cca24cf1424a6dd33c6b139090" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:ae30cc0f093f7c7d86f3297397e0bfba" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:49c70145804456c1bf9071abcb233108" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:md5:248fc1e5da5cc217b4a39175730aea0c" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="urn:lj:livejournal.com:atom1:kadambarid:81472" />
		</rdf:Seq>
	</items>
</channel>

<item rdf:about="urn:md5:f7aa02bd93da6a4c62747fdddc280513">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: Pycon Canada 2012 in Toronto</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2012/Pycon-Canada-2012-in-Toronto</link>
	<content:encoded>Last weekend, at this moment, I was giving a technical talk at &lt;a href=&quot;http://2012.pycon.ca/schedule&quot;&gt;Pycon Canada&lt;/a&gt;, my first. Right now, I am
still wallowing in the fun and warmth of friendships (some old, some new) that
thawed the cold Canadian weather. It was the most mentally simulating,
energy-packed experience I've had.  Oh, wait...I say that about all the
PyCon conferences I attend - Well, this is my second PyCon but the first
speaking gig, and it has, as before, been about meeting some of the smartest
people and having the most intellectually simulating discussions with them,
learning from them and having a whale of a time. Wish all my weekends were this
much fUn! The Python community is known for just that - their fabulously
fantastic community, which attracted me to the language (no, I love the syntax
too) and has kept me hooked.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks to the change in climate (damn you Sandy!), I had a migrane on Friday
morning and I was much happier landing in a slightly warmer and dry climate in
Toronto. Enjoyed the shortest ferry ride of my life and reached the
Metropolitan Hotel by 2pm to find the Google goodie-bags waiting for us at the
hotel room - such a nice surprise, thanks Google!  Went for a long walk in
the afternoon - its a relief to be able to walk around and see the city and its
inhabitants without men bumping into you, or tripping yourself over jutting
stones on the sidewalk (erm...whenever Indian roads have a sidewalk), the
calmness of being able to stop and click pictures without worrying about
someone &amp;quot;accidentally&amp;quot; (it always is, isnt it?) feeling you up while you were
just standing there admiring a monument ........ Oh, well... never mind, you
get the picture!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Later that evening, there was a casual mixer event enabling attendees, speakers
and some &lt;a href=&quot;http://2012.pycon.ca/sponsors&quot;&gt;awesome sponsors&lt;/a&gt; (one of
them being Google, whose Diversity grant made this conference a reality for me)
to register, hang out, and chat before the conference, with food and drinks at
the venue bar open to all... and oh, we ate some &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/diana_clarke/status/267035134639882240/photo/1&quot;&gt;yummy
cake&lt;/a&gt;. Mixers before your conference is a smart way to avoid the rush and
long lines that will queue up to register on the morning of your conference, a
nightmare if you are short on volunteers.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I managed to reach the venue thanks to Suzanne (who I randomly stopped on the
road to ask for directions, instead she ended up dropping me off till the venue
- its amazing how one meets kind souls), met Laura at the registration desk who
saw that every attendee had their badges and tags. Nicola introduced me to
Sheila, who suddenly morphed into a real person instead of an email address
with a picture attached to it. In a global distributed space knit via bits and
bytes, our identities are unequivocally tied to an email, twitter, G+/FB
account now.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Met more interesting people and had the longest discussion with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thok.org/&quot;&gt;Mark Eichin&lt;/a&gt; and his friend Laura, on a range of
technical topics, mobile technology, languages, and not excluding the mandatory
talk about the DFSG and licenses in FOSS - talking legalese is the most
important thing when you meet a DD (j/k). After the party, I returned to the
room, met Laren, another diversity grant recipient room-sharing with me. By
now, the pounding in my head was worse and the pain would not let me sleep, so
I kept re-editing my slides till I was tired enough to sleep.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
On Saturday morning - Day One of the conference, Laren and me walked over to
the venue and I went of into the Green Room where all the speakers were
pampered with &lt;em&gt;food&lt;/em&gt;, some space to sit and work with you laptop,
&lt;em&gt;more food&lt;/em&gt;, chat with other speakers while having &lt;em&gt;even more
food&lt;/em&gt;, but I had no taste buds so I took three Advil's and gave my
&lt;strong&gt;first&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://pyvideo.org/video/1583/mongodb-and-gene-databases&quot;&gt;technical
talk&lt;/a&gt;.  That done, I was free to go and watch talks but instead I went
off to be a volunteer - this is the easiest way to make friends with some
really cool people within the community who welcome and appreciate your
contribution and efforts. Its also very humbling to see the PyConCA board
members and speakers who volunteered to carry in the lunch boxes the caterer
had dropped off.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Post lunch, I attended the &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2012.pycon.ca/talk/61&quot;&gt;Numerical
and Scientific Computing with Python&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; tutorial by David, listened some
great speakers, spoke to more people, had interesting discussions on NLP and
linguistics with &lt;a href=&quot;http://pyvideo.org/video/1587/profiling-for-performance&quot;&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt; and DWF, and
before I knew it, it was the end of the day, which means more food - snacks and
drinks were available at the bar. Did I mention that Pycon-CA pampers you with
food and drinks all through the day. At every break, there was something to
munch on. Every where I looked there were food boxes, fruits / salad boxes,
cookies, coffee, tea, drinks, water bottles, cakes, tacos, samosas (I noticed
that those ran out really quickly as compared to the salads which is not
surprising), strawberry and chocolate, juice, .... ummm..ok, you get the
picture. You were very well-fed and taken care of. At one point I counted the
number of laptops Vs. the food boxes on the table. Guess which was
outnumbered!?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Sunday morning, being the second and final day of the conference, I attended
talks on &lt;a href=&quot;http://pyvideo.org/video/1575/graph-databases-in-python&quot;&gt;Graph databases&lt;/a&gt;
in Python and &lt;a href=&quot;http://pyvideo.org/video/1566/beyond-passwords-secure-authentication-with-mozi&quot;&gt;
Persona&lt;/a&gt; (identity/privacy, which is important to me) and later, &lt;a href=&quot;http://third-bit.com&quot;&gt;Greg Wilson&lt;/a&gt; and a bunch of speakers in the green
room had an interesting conversation on education and knowledge (or
&lt;span class=&quot;url&quot;&gt;the lack thereof) in the current education system, what role
do Universities and schools have to play within the system - are they redundant
with their monolithic rigid structures,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;url url&quot;&gt;MOOC's,
their pro's and cons, and how the internet and technology is changing the
education system, whether sites like Udacity and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;url url&quot;&gt;Coursera (did you know that their business model allows them to sell
your personal details to publishers like McGraw Hill and their ilk, who have
apparently signed on the dotted line) are imparting knowledge to their&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;url url url url&quot;&gt;users and learners at the risk of their privacy?
Where exactly is creativity, mental development, critical thought, knowledge
and learning today? That was more food for thought than the food around the
table. P&lt;/span&gt;ost lunch, I morphed into a Runner - yeah, its that person who
runs behind speakers. Katie and me were deputed to the Main hall speakers and
got to see ALL the talks, including lightning talks, ending with &lt;a href=&quot;http://pyvideo.org/video/1605/science-and-python-retrospective-of-a-mostly-s&quot;&gt;Fernando's
(not-to-be-missed) closing keynote&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Videos:&lt;/h5&gt;
No matter how hard you try, you cannot attend every fantastic talk out there.
When Carl sent across the video link to me, I was stunned by the excellent
production quality. The first thought that crossed my mind was &amp;quot;Wow, that is a
second career right there&amp;quot; and sure enough it is - these excellent videos are
brought to you by &lt;a href=&quot;http://nextdayvideo.com/&quot;&gt;nextdayvideo.com&lt;/a&gt;
:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
* &lt;a href=&quot;http://pyvideo.org/video/1593/server-log-analysis-with-pandas&quot;&gt;Taavi
showing you how pandas get a workout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
* &lt;a href=&quot;http://pyvideo.org/video/1579/i-wish-i-knew-how-to-quit-you-secrets-to-sustain&quot;&gt;
Elizabeth Leddy rocking the Main Hall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
* &lt;a href=&quot;http://pyvideo.org/video/1598/testing-django-with-travis-ci&quot;&gt;Did you
Test today?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
* &lt;a href=&quot;http://pyvideo.org/video/1569/dancing-with-big-data-disco-inferno&quot;&gt;No
conference is complete without a talk on &amp;quot;BigData&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
* &lt;a href=&quot;http://pyvideo.org/video/1599/a-python-sthetic-beauty-and-why-i-python&quot;&gt;Brandon
Rhodes on why he thinks Python is beautiful&lt;/a&gt; (a must see if you are a
beginner to Python)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Wow, this post has gotten too long. Among all the things, I admire the
organizational abilities of the board the most. The conference had &lt;a href=&quot;http://2012.pycon.ca/sponsors&quot;&gt;awesome sponsors&lt;/a&gt; too, one of them being
Google, whose Diversity grant made it possible for me to attend the event.
Initially, when my talk was accepted, I had planned book the bus tickets in
advance so that I could stretch the grant money to enable me to attend both the
days of the conference. When I mentioned this to Diana, she worked her magic,
enabling me to cover my flight bookings and also the hotel stay within the
grant. Amazing team! Kudos to the PyCon-Canada team.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
import pycon&lt;br /&gt;
from pycommunity import &lt;a href=&quot;http://gallery.kateandchris.net/gallery/26579906_hgp68s/2221649244_QDDp9Wq#!i=2221649244&amp;amp;k=QDDp9Wq&quot;&gt;
AwesomePeople&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
canada = pycon.path.abspath(pycon.path.dirname(__file__))&lt;br /&gt;
README = open(pycon.path.join(canada, 'README.rst')).read()&lt;br /&gt;
__version__ = '&lt;a href=&quot;http://gallery.kateandchris.net/gallery/26579906_hgp68s/2221647784_zX7WXNh#%21i=2221647784&amp;amp;k=zX7WXNh&quot;&gt;0.01&lt;/a&gt;'&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;
requires = [&lt;br /&gt;
    '&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/diana_clarke/&quot;&gt;diana&lt;/a&gt;',&lt;br /&gt;
    '&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dlanger&quot;&gt;daniel&lt;/a&gt;',&lt;br /&gt;
    '&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wolever&quot;&gt;david&lt;/a&gt;',&lt;br /&gt;
    '&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kayzh&quot;&gt;kay&lt;/a&gt;',&lt;br /&gt;
    '&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mdibernardo&quot;&gt;micheal&lt;/a&gt;',&lt;br /&gt;
    '&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ncurious&quot;&gt;nicola&lt;/a&gt;',&lt;br /&gt;
    '&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jaaaarel&quot;&gt;taavi&lt;/a&gt;',&lt;br /&gt;
    ]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Patches welcome!&lt;br /&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2012-11-17T05:31:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://barkha.in/blog/?p=164">
	<title>Certified crazy: Restaurant review  Pera, Nice</title>
	<link>http://barkha.in/blog/2012/11/09/restaurant-review-pera-nice/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Last saturday, a late lunch was had at Pera, Nice &amp;#8211; a small, discreet restaurant serving Lebanese food. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ezme, Mechouia, Tabbouleh Libanais, and Hummous were particularly excellent.&lt;br /&gt;
Very good zucchini fritters. Falafel was average.&lt;br /&gt;
Their galettes libanais with ricotta cheese and herbs looked very nice too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good value for money too. Should go again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Address: 2 Descente du Marché 06300 Nice‎&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2012-11-09T10:11:35+00:00</dc:date>
	<dc:creator>barkha</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:md5:2928117ef2887e124743b7bf07fd785e">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: Contributing to Libre software projects</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2012/Contributing-to-Libre-software-projects</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;How do I start contributing to Libre Software?&amp;quot; is a very common question
(I asked that too) one comes across on most FLOSS lists. Today, I posted the
following on a private list and was asked for a public link, so here goes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;SWOT&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are so many Libre software projects to choose from, that choosing one
can be quite confusing when you are starting out. Do yourself a favor and take
a few moments to do a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SWOT_analysis&quot;&gt;SWOT&lt;/a&gt; (Strengths, Weaknesses,
Opportunities and Threats) analysis before you decide to jump onto the Libre
software bandwagon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its better to give yourself time to think (or write down) which technical
area or field interests you:  Which language do you want to program in? Is
it frontend software or backend stuff? Web programming or something else? Do
you like writing system software or application level software? Or, do you like
libraries, prefer working with algorithms/statistical applications, etc..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have figured out your field of interest, its easier to shortlist
something and get started on finding a project to work on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;FINDING A PROJECT&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned above, there are so many Libre software projects that its
overwhelming at the outset. Having figured out your field, dont randomly
visiting a bugtracker and try to solve bugs, which is not a bad idea if you
have only a few hours per week. However, if you want to wade a little deeper,
try using Google to your advantage - read, &lt;a href=&quot;http://google-melange.com&quot;&gt;Google Summer of Code&lt;/a&gt;. This recently concluded
program, has a ready list of organisations to choose from and the 2012 list is
available at: &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/program/accepted_orgs/google/gsoc2012&quot; href=&quot;http://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/program/accepted_orgs/google/gsoc2012&quot; class=&quot;externalLink&quot;&gt;http://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/program/accepted_orgs/google/gsoc2012&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
Besides these few hundred GSoC Orgs, Gnome runs its own outreach program for
women: &lt;a href=&quot;http://live.gnome.org/GnomeWomen/OutreachProgram2012&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://live.gnome.org/GnomeWomen/OutreachProgram2012&lt;/a&gt; and
then, there is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://sophia.estec.esa.int/socis2012/&quot;&gt;European
Space Agency&lt;/a&gt;, which is (sadly) only open to EU students. However, if you
are interested in working outside of the SoC span, projects are always
interested in contributors and would welcome your efforts 24x7x365. That said,
these SoC tasks require a longer commitment in terms of time, so you need to
decide what you want to do.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;FOUND A TASK, WHAT NEXT?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
After you have searched Melange (or ESA) for keywords of your choice, visit
each organisations Ideas page, where you will find a list of tasks ranked as
per preference or difficulty level (This entirely depends on the Org).
&lt;strong&gt;Remember to cross-check with the Melange page if the task has already
been completed via GSoC, or not&lt;/strong&gt;. If a task is still available, find
out what is required to get started on it and prepare a short abstract. This
will help you to..&lt;br /&gt;
- figure out the development stack vis-a-vis your skillset,&lt;br /&gt;
- realise how much time and effort is required to bridge the gap, if any
;&lt;br /&gt;
- prepare a timeline estimate. (Dont obsess over this as its just an estimate
and it will vary if the Org changes any requirements.)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
These done, talk to the Org - &lt;strong&gt;always, Always, ALWAYS talk to the Org
_before_ you start work on anything&lt;/strong&gt;. Just because a task is listed on
the Ideas page does not mean its a part of their workflow (which can always
change), nor is the opposite true. The best way to find out is to talk to them,
first. Again, remember that these SoC tasks require a longer commitment in
terms of time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;COMMUNICATING WITH LIBRE COMMUNITIES&lt;/h5&gt;
Most Libre projects have their own communication channels. This could be via
Mailing lists or Forums, including IRC channels on dedicated servers or on
freenode. Its important to work with them via these public channels and that
means learning to communicate and not worry about asking silly (psst..there are
none) questions. Communicating with the core developer and/or mentors and
community of users is crucial - they can be an invaluable source for ideas and
helpful hints.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many projects have separate lists (and IRC channels) for users and
developers. Join them and introduce yourself (or lurk around to get a hang of
how things work) and when you are ready, do talk about the task you want to
work on. A development mailing list, where the core developers would be
available, is distinguishable via the &amp;quot;*-devel&amp;quot; mailing address. Same is true
for IRC channels - If you like CLI tools, try Irssi or Quassel if you want a
GUI client. Pick your poison from this &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IRC_clients#Clients&quot;&gt;list of IRC
clients&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;EXPERIMENT WITH THE DEVELOPMENT STACK&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, and most importantly, you must be comfortable working with the
software the project uses - that means, you should be able to clone and get the
software to install and work on your local machine. Here, communicating with
your Org helps - You can ask for help if you have hardware or software issues,
clarify installation and dependency issues, etc... No software works flawlessly
(else, people would be out of jobs :)) and Libre software is no exception - the
only difference being &amp;quot;software development on a libre/public scale&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another aspect of getting familiar with the development stack is
familiarizing yourself with the projects internal system - Since, each project
uses its own &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bug_tracking_system&quot;&gt;bug
tracker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Distributed_version_control_system&quot;&gt;DVCS&lt;/a&gt;,
Wiki for documentation, Email/Forum and IRC communication system ; take some
time to get familiar with each of these. If you plan to stick around for any
length of time, you would be using some, or, all the software stacks they use
on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your transition from newbie to active contributor is a lot faster when you
are comfortable with the development stack. Doing your homework will give you
the confidence required to grok it enough to start working on the code-base,
suggest changes or solve bugs, etc..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope these suggestions help you find your niche learning shell to
contribute to, and of course, welcome to the Libre software. Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2012-08-29T18:26:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:md5:e4ae29bcb8cd3c4ca4aa106d812c8e6c">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: Rest in peace Lawgon</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2012/Rest-in-peace-Lawgon</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Am breaking a long hiatus from blogging to report a really sad news ::
Kenneth Gonsalves, (lawgon on IRC), a long time Free/Libre software (especially
INPycon) contributor is no more. When I first saw &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/inpycon/2012-August/005485.html&quot;&gt;this
mail&lt;/a&gt; in my inbox, I could not believe it was true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first interaction with Lawgon was via the LinuxChix mailing lists. Back
then, I was surprised to see posts from a &amp;quot;nilgiris&amp;quot; domain name and I assumed
he was an USA-NRI actively posting on their lists. Later, the Mumbai-LUG list
when I had tried to install his &amp;quot;avsap&amp;quot; accounting software ~ it would not work
on my machine and I wrote him a mail with the gory error details. Finally, in
2007, I met &amp;quot;lawgon&amp;quot; on IRC, ##linux-india. I was never an IRC person but when
he got banned from the channel, I had a long argument with Devdas (f3ew on IRC)
about it - mostly because I felt that the rules were not clear, and even more
importantly, felt that rules ought to be implemented uniformly, sans
cronyism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few moons later, I met him IRL for the first time at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://svaksha.com/post/2009/National-coalition-for-Libre-software&quot;&gt;first formation meet for
Fosscomm&lt;/a&gt; and sat next to him through the whole meeting. In my eyes, he was
like a father-figure, a person you can talk to freely, someone who didnt see IT
and FLOSS as the road to self-publicity, fame and riches. Rather, he saw Libre
software as I did - &lt;strong&gt;of, for and by the people&lt;/strong&gt;. It was nice
talking to him and hear the stories via the work he had done at
NRC-Foss/AU-KBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was someone I respected because unlike some FOSS people, he actually
wrote and released his code publicly: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitbucket.org/lawgon&quot;&gt;https://bitbucket.org/lawgon&lt;/a&gt;, and worked
within the community, had no illusions or superiority complex about himself.
Most of us in the FLOSS community were his kids age and in my interactions I
didnt find him patronizing nor elitist in &amp;quot;demanding&amp;quot; we respect his age. Quite
the opposite, he never hesitated to ask for technical help from people younger
than him, quite ego less. His fiery rants on his blog (&lt;a href=&quot;http://lawgon.livejournal.com/&quot;&gt;http://lawgon.livejournal.com/&lt;/a&gt;) always
made me chuckle. There are very few blogs I follow and thusfar, I've read every
post of his - strong opinions peppered with character. His own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his list communication, he could be quite blunt in his comments, and I've
had my moments sparring with him on the lists, but if you take a moment to look
behind the scenes, his honesty and sincerity towards Libre software showed. I
remember his mail asking me not to leave the Mumbai LUG list and my response on
the kind of Libre community (the lack thereof) we foster, which, to my
surprise, found an echo with him. I remember his long email rant (about someone
which I wont get into in public) where he mentioned &amp;quot;...and I'm scared of you&amp;quot;
~ yeah, I too scrubbed my eyes and smiled at his droll sense of humor, as I
typed out an apology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember his IRC comment that he wanted his daughter to meet me and my
curiosity piqued ~ this was before I had met him in real life and going by the
stereotypical Indian fathers attitude, I very much doubted if they would want
their daughters to be like me. Or maybe it was his sense of humor - I'll never
know!? Some moons later an email asking for some information on &amp;quot;legal rights
of women in India&amp;quot; for her coursework, IRC discussions on virtualenvwrapper (he
asked me why I wanted to use it and for a moment I thought he was testing me --
I could not imagine a longtime Python developer (atleast a lot longer than me)
asking me that, unless he was pulling my leg or if it was an interview
question), discussing a recent Python workshop he held at Kerala, and so many
other interactions... {Edit1:: His recent mail on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ae.iitm.ac.in/pipermail/ilugc/2012-July/072575.html&quot;&gt;the open
source business model&lt;/a&gt; has some excellent advice for wannabe
entrepreneurs.}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was hoping to meet him at InPycon this year but now the conference wont be
the same without him. I hope and pray his family finds the strength to carry on
without him and may his soul rest in peace! You will be missed Lawgon..and try
not to kickstart a &amp;quot;GPL Vs. BSD&amp;quot; argument in heaven!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2012-08-03T12:33:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3835450307118836937.post-890022578992145982">
	<title>All things technical...: Beacon with Google AJAXSLT</title>
	<link>http://meworkstoo.blogspot.com/2012/06/beacon-with-google-ajaxslt.html</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;div id=&quot;inbdy&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;I was experimenting with XSL transformations on client side so that&amp;nbsp;we could make Beacon embed-able.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;It will be useful if we can pull&amp;nbsp;this off because&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;it will help us concentrate on the Editor itself and&amp;nbsp;leave the authentication and workflow to the services that would&amp;nbsp;like to use Beacon for editing.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;This will also help in easier adoption&amp;nbsp;by various organizations as they won't have to set up a different&amp;nbsp;service and look for ways to integrate their workflow with Beacon's.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jongma.org/webtools/jquery/#xslt&quot;&gt;jquery.xslt.js&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(code &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jongma.org/webtools/jquery/jquery.xslt.js&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)is a JQuery wrapper around the &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/ajaxslt/&quot;&gt;Google AJAXSLT&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;project which fits in in my opinion because Beacon uses JQuery&amp;nbsp;extensively and Google AJAXSLT gives us a browser independent&amp;nbsp;solution that is essential for Beacon to be adopted.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;I looked at the demo code and set up a similar environment in&amp;nbsp;localhost (basically reusing the template XML and &amp;nbsp;XSL files the&amp;nbsp;docbook plugin folder of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/satya/beacon/tree/master/beacon/plugins/docbook/xml&quot;&gt;Beacon&lt;/a&gt; and CSS and media files from&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/satya/beacon/tree/master/beacon&quot;&gt;Beacon&lt;/a&gt; and placing them under &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;/var/www/html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt; along with the&amp;nbsp;test HTML as below:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC &quot;-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Strict//EN&quot; &quot;http://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/url?sa=D&amp;amp;q=www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-strict.dtd&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNGhDKVpCsVuY65uh9MOgyjW8IzXVA&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-strict.dtd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&quot;&amp;gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;XSLT Test&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html;charset=utf-8&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; href=&quot;docbook.css&quot;/&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div id=&quot;output&quot; style=&quot;padding: 2px;&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;jquery.min.js&quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt; /script&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;jquery.xslt.js&quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt; /script&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;(function() {&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;// The magic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;$('#output').xslt({xmlUrl:'test.xml', xslUrl:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;'docbook2html.xsl'});&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;});&lt;br /&gt; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The resulting window looked like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/open?id=0B8l35ArmWgUKVmZRZUh1bjk2a0k&quot;&gt;screenshot&lt;/a&gt; which was really&amp;nbsp;exciting but I was running into the problem that the text in the&amp;nbsp;paragraphs&amp;nbsp;was missing. I added the XSL template for para as below:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;xsl:template match=&quot;para&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;p title=&quot;docbookPara&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;xsl:value-of select=&quot;.&quot; /&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;xsl:apply-templates /&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/xsl:template&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;This fixed most of the problems as shown in screenshots &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/open?id=0B8l35ArmWgUKV3JKVGR3TGQ1ZGM&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/open?id=0B8l35ArmWgUKTGlQQ19rS2FCblU&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;But now I'm stuck at a rather weird issue. The nested tags don't&amp;nbsp;function&amp;nbsp;properly.&amp;nbsp;Trying to come up with the shortest bit of XSL and XML that show the&amp;nbsp;issue, if my XSL is:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;ISO-8859-1&quot;?&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;xsl:stylesheet&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;lt; xsl:template match=&quot;/&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;xsl:apply-templates select=&quot;para&quot;/&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;/xsl:template&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;xsl:template match=&quot;para&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;xsl:value-of select=&quot;.&quot;/&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;xsl:apply-templates /&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;/xsl:template&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;xsl:template match=&quot;bold&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;xsl:value-of select=&quot;.&quot;/&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;xsl:apply-templates /&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/xsl:stylesheet&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;The XML snippet &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;para&amp;gt; Hello&amp;lt;bold&amp;gt;World&amp;lt;/bold&amp;gt;!&amp;lt;/para&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;results in &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Hello World!&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;World&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;I tried to find out on #xml on Freenode, and according to them,&amp;nbsp;&amp;lt; ?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;ISO-8859-1&quot;?&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;xsl:stylesheet&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;xsl:template match=&quot;/&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;xsl:apply-templates select=&quot;para&quot;/&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;/xsl:template&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;xsl:template match=&quot;para&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;xsl:apply-templates /&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;/xsl:template&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;xsl:template match=&quot;bold&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;xsl:apply-templates /&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;/xsl:template&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;/xsl:stylesheet&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;should work but removing the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;xsl:value-of select=&quot;.&quot;/&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt; removes the&amp;nbsp;entire text altogether.&amp;nbsp;Any suggestions on how I can fix this?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/3835450307118836937-890022578992145982?l=meworkstoo.blogspot.com&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2012-06-05T14:48:47+00:00</dc:date>
	<dc:creator>satya</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://archu.wordpress.com/?p=803">
	<title>Archu's Cyberspace...!: archu</title>
	<link>http://archu.wordpress.com/2012/05/18/aradhana/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I guess she is the best possible happiness that I have felt in my life. Though it was troublesome throughout my entire journey of pregnancy, and also coping up with post pregnancy issues, are all worth it when she just looks at me and smiles. I had several priorities in my life, friends, family, career.. everything has taken a back stage after her arrival. Tomorrow she s completing 2 months of her life and it sure does feel like I have given birth to her just yesterday !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://archu.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/video0009_0000015695.jpg?w=500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;zemanta-pixie&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;zemanta-pixie-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://img.zemanta.com/pixy.gif?x-id=15fcee25-367b-8107-8339-8616de33003f&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/archu.wordpress.com/803/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/archu.wordpress.com/803/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=archu.wordpress.com&amp;#038;blog=373911&amp;#038;post=803&amp;#038;subd=archu&amp;#038;ref=&amp;#038;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2012-05-17T23:09:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:md5:824ec2573e073b517a6b354446028b7f">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: Programming with Julia</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2012/Programming-with-Julia</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Using (or talking) about R makes me want to rant sometimes and if you've
ever written a line of Fortran code, you would have certainly wanted to
experiment with a new language stack for scientific programming. Yup, I am
aware of scipy, numpy, sympy, sage, et al.. and despite their existence, when I
came across this &lt;a href=&quot;http://mailman.linuxchix.org/pipermail/indichix/2012-January/001774.html&quot;&gt;language
for scientific programming in January this year&lt;/a&gt;, sheer curiosity** made me
give it a spin.&lt;/p&gt;
Starting the year with a scientific language that has clean syntax and some
nicer documentation made me feel warm and fuzzy, until, it refused to build due
to a BLAS dependency. That problem didnt last for long though, as I was able to
pull a fresh commit which had fixed this issue. Its nice to see an active team
having interesting (read, sane) development discussions. A Matlab coder has
opined &lt;a href=&quot;http://2pif.info/op/julia.html&quot;&gt;thus about Julia&lt;/a&gt; while an R
programmer has done a comparison between &lt;a href=&quot;http://vincebuffalo.org/2012/03/07/thoughts-on-julia.html&quot;&gt;Julia and R&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;After some trial-and-error, I managed to grok its syntax, enough to rewrite
an old fortran code in JuliaLang [Julia is still pre-release and I ran Version
0.0.0+1331430882.r69af from Commit 69afb7032d (2012-03-11 07:39:42)]:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#!/usr/bin/env julia&lt;br /&gt;
# -*- coding: utf-8 -*-&lt;br /&gt;
#*****************************************************************************&lt;br /&gt;

# COPYRIGHT (C) 2012 VidAyer &amp;lt;vid@svaksha.com&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
# LICENSE: GNU AGPLv3, http://www.gnu.org/licenses/agpl-3.0.html&lt;br /&gt;
#*****************************************************************************&lt;br /&gt;

#
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pearson_correlation#Geometric_interpretation&lt;br /&gt;
# Example, suppose 5 countries have gross national products&lt;br /&gt;
# of 1, 2, 3, 5, and 8 billion dollars, resp. Suppose these 5 countries&lt;br /&gt;
# (in the same order) are found to have 11%, 12%, 13%, 15%, and&lt;br /&gt;
# 18% poverty. Then let x and y be ordered 5-element vectors containing&lt;br /&gt;
# the above data: x = (1, 2, 3, 5, 8) and y = (0.11, 0.12, 0.13, 0.15,
0.18).&lt;br /&gt;
#*****************************************************************************&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;
gnp = [1, 2, 3, 5, 8]&lt;br /&gt;
poverty = [0.11, 0.12, 0.13, 0.15, 0.18]&lt;br /&gt;
vectorgnpgnp = 0.0&lt;br /&gt;
vectorpovertypoverty = 0.0&lt;br /&gt;
vectorgnppoverty = 0.0&lt;br /&gt;
costheta = 0.0&lt;br /&gt;
n = 1.0&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
vectorgnpgnp = vectorgnpgnp + gnp[n]*gnp[n]&lt;br /&gt;
vectorpovertypoverty = vectorpovertypoverty + poverty[n]*poverty[n]&lt;br /&gt;
vectorgnppoverty = vectorgnppoverty + gnp[n]*poverty[n]&lt;br /&gt;
costheta = vectorgnppoverty /
(sqrt(vectorgnpgnp)*sqrt(vectorpovertypoverty))&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
# Terminal Out&lt;br /&gt;
println(&amp;quot;The Vector product value of Cos Theta is: &amp;quot;,costheta)   #
correct value should be 0.9208   &lt;br /&gt;
println(&amp;quot;The Vector product of GNP and Poverty coordinates: 
&amp;quot;,vectorgnppoverty) # correct value should be 2.930   &lt;br /&gt;
println(&amp;quot;The Vector product of GNP is:  &amp;quot;,vectorgnpgnp) # correct value
should be 103.0   &lt;br /&gt;
println(&amp;quot;The Vector product of Poverty coordinates is: 
&amp;quot;,vectorpovertypoverty) # correct value should be 0.9830E-01&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was avoiding blogging this here as I think code belongs in a DVCS, not in a
blog but I've intentionally not uploaded this program because its not fully
functional yet -- see my comments within the code. When I cross-check the
results from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/svaksha/algorithms-fortran95/blob/master/pearsonCorrelationAlGeo.f95&quot;&gt;
fortran code&lt;/a&gt; (or as mentioned in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pearson_correlation#Geometric_interpretation&quot;&gt;WP
page --Geometric_interpretation&lt;/a&gt;.) I find &amp;quot;sqrt&amp;quot; isnt working as it should
-- I need to figure out the syntax a wee bit more, so I'll push this only if it
works perfectly.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
** PS: That it was named after a woman (or atleast I like to think so) isnt
what prompted my interest! No kidding!</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2012-03-11T04:16:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:lj:livejournal.com:atom1:kadambarid:82520">
	<title>kadambarid: Portraits and Landscapes</title>
	<link>http://kadambarid.livejournal.com/82520.html</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;div&gt;It was twilight. Almost. The setting sun visible between two peaks of a mountain range, reminding one of the crayon masterpieces that kindergarten kids wave into existence. The clear, blue, and cloudless sky of the day somehow transforms into a haze of purple and diffused pink. The flat desert terrain encapsulated by towering, slaty mountains, almost the color of &lt;i&gt;obsidian&lt;/i&gt; in the play of glows and shadows. I had picked up a fragment of the black glass just that morning, a treasured keepsake from a harsh land.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We were in the Saline Valley, an arid landscape in the rain shadow of the massive Sierra-Nevada mountains in California. This was now officially a part of the Death Valley National Park, the northern outpost of the Mojave desert's three national parks. Any imagery that comes to mind when you think of the Death Valley is vastly representative of the region. An average visual would involve sand dunes, shrubs that speckle an almost alien landscape, and not a soul as far as the eye can see. This would not be far off the mark. The name might be a tad too harsh though, with the prospectors during the &lt;i&gt;Gold Rush&lt;/i&gt; to be blamed for the misnomer. The name notwithstanding, there are statistically far fewer deaths here than in your average American town ...&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000g9cst/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;239&quot; src=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000g9cst/s320x240&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000gbta0/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;239&quot; src=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000gbta0/s320x240&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We were in the company of close friends, veterans of the area, who wanted this Indian couple to experience the &lt;i&gt;Great American Outdoors&lt;/i&gt;, while they could drown in &lt;i&gt;Tequila&lt;/i&gt; around the bonfire, under a chilly desert moon. The stocky and cheerful American computational neuroscientist who knows the terrain like the back of his hand, and the lanky South African computer scientist, his comrade in arms, made up the duo who masterminded the trip. My husband and I just left things to the experts. Our long-weekend camping trip in the summer of 2010 to the Death Valley National Park also traversed the ghost town of Bodie, the picturesque little town of Bridgeport -- the gateway to the desert, the mysterious Lake Mono and her curious &lt;i&gt;tuftas&lt;/i&gt;, setting up camp in the remote but spectacular Saline Valley, lazing around in the three lovely natural &lt;i&gt;hot springs&lt;/i&gt; -- gorgeous &lt;i&gt;oases&lt;/i&gt; in the middle of the desert, and returning to Oakland via the Yosemite National Park, with lots of adventure thrown in for good measure.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000gd7bs/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;239&quot; src=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000gd7bs/s320x240&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000gkfe8/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;239&quot; src=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000gkfe8/s320x240&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;It was our second day there. We had met a host of colorful personalities at the hot springs, which being an oasis in the desert attracted a smattering of people who would amble in like animals to a watering hole in the African &lt;i&gt;savannah&lt;/i&gt;. Not far from the entrance were some signposts. One read '&lt;i&gt;Bare Crossing&lt;/i&gt;' in bold black letters, while the other said '&lt;i&gt;Clothing Optional&lt;/i&gt;'. If you were wearing a swimsuit, you were deemed overdressed. To add to the excitement, an ultra-light plane landed right on the flat desert, in the absence of an airstrip. A couple stepped out and announced that they had 'swung by' for an impromptu picnic. After a day of delightful lazing in the most 'developed' of the hot springs, we decided to head back to base camp, which had been set up near the farthest of the hot springs and one that attracted a surprising number of bats. And thankfully no throngs of people. Somewhere towards the middle of this route between the two hot springs, stood a gnarled old man by an easel and surrounded by an assortment of paintings, tubes of paint, brushes of varying sizes, all kinds of art &lt;i&gt;paraphernalia&lt;/i&gt;, and some camping odds and ends. The back of his dusty &lt;i&gt;SUV&lt;/i&gt; was propped open, with a curious arrangement of grab-n-go art stuff. We decided to stop and chat, primarily because of the paintings haphazardly strewn all around the car, almost arranging themselves in a natural gallery with the sublime lighting of the setting sun to boot. The fact that he was the first fully-dressed person we had seen in more than a day might have also had something to do with it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He was facing the sun, or rather, he was facing the easel which in turn had the scenery he was trying to capture as backdrop with the intrusive sun encroaching upon it. He was wearing a dirty full-sleeve shirt that must have once been a healthy white, loose knee-length work pants in khakhi, and an apron streaked with dull fingerprints - vestiges of occasional hand-wiping. The apron's current condition made it almost impossible to guess the original color of the cloth. Comfortable suede shoes, a rather tame cowboy hat that would have been of scant protection in the sun especially if it were at its vicious best, round-rimmed spectacles, and a broad welcoming grin completed the outfit. It was the sort of quiet smile that somehow managed to remind you of a sigh of relief. It was also the kind of benign smile one would wear when opening the door to expected guests. He put down his palette and brush, after a few strokes of some shade of yellow. The others wandered off to look at the landscape and figure out which portion of it was captured in which painting of his.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000grsgp/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;239&quot; src=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000grsgp/s320x240&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000gtw0c/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;239&quot; src=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000gtw0c/s320x240&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He walked up to me at my vantage point of watching the artist at work, occasionally turning to see some of his paintings, and a view of the vanishing sun straight ahead, wiping his grimy hands on a well-used piece of cloth. He shook my hands, introduced himself, and handed me his business card - the fleeting thought that I might be a potential customer seemed to call for the nicety. He seemed to be in a chatty mood and after a brief round of introductions started reminiscing. Surprisingly, he had started painting rather late in life, when he was past the age of sixty. Before he retired, he had been working either in a law firm or was dabbling in finance - I do not quite remember which. His second wife had been an artist and introduced him to oil on canvas. She was a lot younger than him and taught him many things, art included. When they separated, he somehow drifted towards the medium and started focusing on landscapes. He started coming to the Death Valley, enjoying the solitude and inspired by the terrain. The play of shadows, the minute variations in colors, and capturing the surreal landscape were challenges that had him addicted, a drug that had him visit again and again. Year after year. The harsh environment and the scorching sun beating down actually helped him focus.&amp;nbsp; Was it not boring to come to the same place each time? He insisted that it was not, that the land was dynamic, and to capture its mood and essence was quite a challenge. He also visited other interesting areas but preferred the valley for its quiet and solitude. He also enjoyed coming to the Death Valley for another reason - it helped him improve his skills in his other hobby, tracking. He had attended some classes on tracking wildlife at the University and he liked honing it here. Pug marks, scat, scents, sounds, feathers, marking, and miscellaneous spoor. All clues and hints to fathom, discern, and unravel the wild mysteries in the desert trails. It is quite fascinating what the land reveals and what it hides. Another challenge, this time an analytical process as opposed to his first love of the creative.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000gqkfw/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;239&quot; src=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000gqkfw/s320x240&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000gaqxf/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;239&quot; src=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000gaqxf/s320x240&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Why was he here? Was it the solitude, an escape from banality? A solitude in a stark environment that seemingly helps one get through the pain of loneliness in a city. A solitude that is a balm to loneliness and assuages it just enough to return to the hordes. Maybe it was that reflection that helped him open up to a stranger ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What was it that made me want to stop and chat with him? Maybe it was how out-of-place he was, like a fish out of water -- an artist, alone, in a rugged and demanding land that looks deceptively lifeless. Maybe it was the picture of him creating something with a smile and hum, a visible joy that was not lost in translation. Maybe it was the obscure way in which he stood out and yet blended with the landscape, how unobtrusive yet obvious he was. Maybe it was the irony of a luxurious creative pursuit against the backdrop of a desolate world. Maybe it was his almost arrogant fearlessness in standing there alone against the forces of nature, all the while tracing them ... Maybe it was all that and more.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;---&lt;br /&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.expedia.co.in/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Expedia&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.indiblogger.in/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Indiblogger&lt;/a&gt; for finally inspiring me to sit down and write.</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2012-02-29T17:57:42+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://archu.wordpress.com/?p=792">
	<title>Archu's Cyberspace...!: archu</title>
	<link>http://archu.wordpress.com/2011/12/27/linux-mint-2/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I had a hard disk crash few months back and my 120GB HDD of my laptop retired. I was planning to get an upgraded HDD for 500GB and install the visa basic which came with the laptop. Then a thought came thru Govind to try &lt;a href=&quot;http://linuxmint.com/&quot;&gt;Linux Mint&lt;/a&gt;. I felt why not after all those years trying several linux distros, I felt really nothing was out of box and always I had to spend countless nights trying to figure things out through friends and forums. I really feel that this one has better desktop approach than most of the distros I tried few years back. Though I did not like the fancy KDE gimmicks, felt that gnome upgrade was quite simple and easy. It had answers to all my requirements for day today computer usage and was surprised to see few interesting apps that I could use to make my life easier, which in windows I would have to scoot for freewares or think abt trials/cracks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What prompted me to write this entry is after reading this &lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.com/open-source/news/2011/12/two-decades-of-linux-the-big-open-source-stories-of-2011.ars&quot;&gt;article &lt;/a&gt;felt that people should try this one if there is a spare pc or run into misfortune of system crashes. Its really a worthy try. I am currently not thinking of running into windows unless I require some proprietary work related s/w to be installed. Happy computing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;zemanta-pixie&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;zemanta-pixie-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://img.zemanta.com/pixy.gif?x-id=f7c5e52a-9078-81d6-900a-25c8d8961575&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/archu.wordpress.com/792/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/archu.wordpress.com/792/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=archu.wordpress.com&amp;#038;blog=373911&amp;#038;post=792&amp;#038;subd=archu&amp;#038;ref=&amp;#038;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-12-27T17:38:56+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://archu.wordpress.com/?p=786">
	<title>Archu's Cyberspace...!: archu</title>
	<link>http://archu.wordpress.com/2011/12/27/pms-visit-not-so-eventful-esp-to-busy-office-goers/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The most irritating part of any politician or higher level govt officials visit is the special traffic regulations made to make everyone but their life easier.. for more info read this &lt;a href=&quot;http://newstodaynet.com/newsindex.php?id=27725%20&amp;amp;%20section=7&quot;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was very much angry to see that entire GST road stretch was kept free of all vehicles for smooth travel of our PM. I am not sure why he couldnt take the ariel route and save him from thousands of curses people shower esp during such occasions! Why cant he fly to Karaikudi? he can do it, but people taking pathetic bus routes via guindy cannot even afford hiked bus fares. I think its better time for politicians to think sensibly in such things if not improving nation, which is not their field of expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;zemanta-pixie&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;zemanta-pixie-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://img.zemanta.com/pixy.gif?x-id=5aa6445c-379e-8d06-a0c7-a0c8f945f139&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/archu.wordpress.com/786/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/archu.wordpress.com/786/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=archu.wordpress.com&amp;#038;blog=373911&amp;#038;post=786&amp;#038;subd=archu&amp;#038;ref=&amp;#038;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-12-26T18:31:57+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://archu.wordpress.com/?p=781">
	<title>Archu's Cyberspace...!: archu</title>
	<link>http://archu.wordpress.com/2011/12/23/radhas-wedding-kumbakonam/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; We started by 12-dec night. Though we booked in first class A/C in Rockfort express, boarding the train in tambaram was bit of a struggle as A/C coaches were not together and esp the first class A/c was seperated. The train was supposed to halt for jus couple of mins and we had to hurry to the First AC compartment. I couldn&amp;#8217;t run and we boarded the train few compartments before in 3rd AC compartments. Train started almost immediately after we boarded. We finally reached our respective coach and timing was perfect that train reached chengelpet station. Athai and athimber were waiting there with much anticipation. After few minutes we started sleeping and train was going like a rocking coach. I felt very difficult and uncomfortable, had to sit for few minutes throughout the night and somehow manage. Can relate this to maatu vandi which is bit faster with less bumpy roads!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we reached Kumbakonam, we were happy that there were no stairs like in Tambaram. We saw Balaji, Govind&amp;#8217;s cousin awaiting our arrival. We chose to take a cab instead of van since I felt it would delay and also van was not comfortable after the tiresome journey. We paid 200/- and reached the mandapam in 20 mins. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the train reached there around 7:45 only, the Jathagarna Namagarnam function was over. We dressed up and everyone went to have breakfast and coffee. Appa got pongal and vadai for me and I had it after long time. Appa, amma, athai, athimber left to tour on some temples. I was left chatting with Radha and other ppl there. Later once ppl are back frm temple, we got ready for the Nitchaythartham function in the evening. It happened in the Uppiliappan kovil mandapam. Since next day it was early morning muhurtham we planned to sleep early, but finally after doing all talking we slept around 11 I guess. Before I was ready in the morning the Unjal function started and I came perfectly when they were coming back to medai. Wedding was over in a couple of hours. Had gud time seeing the events and taking snaps. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://archu.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/pic.jpg?w=500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appa and Amma again went to temples and rain started to pour outside as I was thinking of going to Kovil. Finally dropped the plan and went on to sleep. Woke up later and thought of talking with Radha, but she went for marriage registration and other formalities. So I started packing for the night return journey. Since its the same train, I mentally prepared myself for the worst conditions. There was a kalyana urchavam organised by my inlaws in the temple, so was attending that in the evening. Came back and packed everything and left to station bit early. But since it was first platform, we need not climb any stairs. Also we got a stroller and porter to take our luggages. Rched tambaram in the wee hours of the morning and were welcomed by mild rain which later turned to a heavier one. Finally reached home and slept for few hrs to gain back basic energy! &lt;img src=&quot;http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; class=&quot;wp-smiley&quot; /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;zemanta-pixie&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;zemanta-pixie-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://img.zemanta.com/pixy.gif?x-id=d5f699ca-4723-89b3-a04d-c9965c32aec3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/archu.wordpress.com/781/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/archu.wordpress.com/781/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=archu.wordpress.com&amp;#038;blog=373911&amp;#038;post=781&amp;#038;subd=archu&amp;#038;ref=&amp;#038;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-12-23T16:34:34+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://archu.wordpress.com/?p=774">
	<title>Archu's Cyberspace...!: archu</title>
	<link>http://archu.wordpress.com/2011/12/08/sehwag-219-b149-4s-25-6s7/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Have watched all mokkai matches, and even the last ODI which we lost.. missed this one &lt;img src=&quot;http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif&quot; alt=&quot;:(&quot; class=&quot;wp-smiley&quot; /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Even did not track the score.. should catch atleast highlights. But looks like highlights will have more than India&amp;#8217;s total in last match &lt;img src=&quot;http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; class=&quot;wp-smiley&quot; /&gt;  What an entertainment !&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.espncricinfo.com/db/PICTURES/CMS/139900/139931.jpg&quot; width=&quot;537&quot; height=&quot;358&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;zemanta-pixie&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;zemanta-pixie-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://img.zemanta.com/pixy.gif?x-id=13d50704-3974-8539-877b-6689b3508a66&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/archu.wordpress.com/774/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/archu.wordpress.com/774/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=archu.wordpress.com&amp;#038;blog=373911&amp;#038;post=774&amp;#038;subd=archu&amp;#038;ref=&amp;#038;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-12-08T15:24:07+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://archu.wordpress.com/?p=771">
	<title>Archu's Cyberspace...!: archu</title>
	<link>http://archu.wordpress.com/2011/12/06/lightwave/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I was following some lightwave webminars and articles these days closely. Lot of things displayed there make me think where the future telecom would be ..! decade started with 1G and already there are trials of 500G. I guess the near life like experience, which is currently present only in corporate will be available to the public. Though in ads of 3g i see them, but not that satisfactory. Since I work in a wider spectrum knowing the placing of the products and the issues faced, it really looks interesting how all this development happened in 2-3 decades. Can&amp;#8217;t imagine like the fiction author &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sujatha_Rangarajan&quot;&gt;Sujatha&lt;/a&gt; who predicted lot of current advancements. More and more telecom startups are coming up, and more and more are acquired by the giants like &lt;a href=&quot;http://cisco.com&quot;&gt;Cisco&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://ciena.com&quot;&gt;Ciena&lt;/a&gt; especially in the optical arena. Would post a detailed info after observing their moves in the coming year, but for sure their share in all the areas are increasing providing the customers with variety to choose from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;zemanta-pixie&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;zemanta-pixie-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://img.zemanta.com/pixy.gif?x-id=47da0348-873a-80ed-837b-14b6c8d7a5ed&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/archu.wordpress.com/771/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/archu.wordpress.com/771/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=archu.wordpress.com&amp;#038;blog=373911&amp;#038;post=771&amp;#038;subd=archu&amp;#038;ref=&amp;#038;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-12-06T17:00:43+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://archu.wordpress.com/?p=765">
	<title>Archu's Cyberspace...!: archu</title>
	<link>http://archu.wordpress.com/2011/12/05/a-piece-of-land/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Its very difficult these days to acquire a piece of land either as investment or to stay there.. especially in the case of metros. If the flat/ind home is got in outskirts people comment about its location, if its got in city, people tell its very dingy.. Only people with parental or other financial support are able to own a house before they turn 30. In olden days building home will be a lifetime dream, which mostly happens between 40-50 yrs on average, now even an 25 yr old owns a flat somewhere in the city or in the native. Real estate agents seem to have used this to the core. I have been to many building expos, fairs, where the people just drop in and book the flat, not even visiting the location. I donot know whether they are rich, or lazy or simply falling under the trusting category.. not sure though.. Seeing the outskirts skyscrappers and crorepathis getting houses in RA purams, I am not sure what is the best profession to build a home with decent space these days.. Really fingers crossed :-X&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A flat that costed 15 lacs before 5 yrs is now 35-40 lacs, irrespective of the location, if its in a metro its the hike ratio.. Salaries hav also increased, so are the EMIs, and also the expectations from near and dear ones..!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/archu.wordpress.com/765/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/archu.wordpress.com/765/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=archu.wordpress.com&amp;#038;blog=373911&amp;#038;post=765&amp;#038;subd=archu&amp;#038;ref=&amp;#038;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-12-05T18:08:06+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3835450307118836937.post-8156460927610810513">
	<title>All things technical...: Talk at FUDCon.in</title>
	<link>http://meworkstoo.blogspot.com/2011/11/talk-at-fudconin.html</link>
	<content:encoded>After working with JBoss and Drools for more than an year at Red Hat, I am giving my first JBoss talk!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I am giving an introduction to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jboss.org/drools&quot;&gt;JBoss Drools&lt;/a&gt; (An open source Business Rules Integration Platform).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As the expected audience is primarily students, I intend to give them a short background of expert systems, give them an idea about inference engines and their applications in the industry using drools as an example.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As the schedule permits only 40 mins for the talk and 10 mins for Q&amp;amp;A, I'll show them how to make a simple application using drools if time permits.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Being a happy drools user for quite sometime, I really hope I am able to convince people to give it a try :)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Oh and now is the time for the uber-cute FUDCon's Happy Guy!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fudcon.in/&quot; title=&quot;FUDCon Pune 2011&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://fedoraproject.org/w/uploads/4/40/Button3-going.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/3835450307118836937-8156460927610810513?l=meworkstoo.blogspot.com&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-11-02T14:44:11+00:00</dc:date>
	<dc:creator>satya</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://amrita.dgplug.org/?p=57">
	<title>Amrita Mukherjee: Time for some new thoughts…</title>
	<link>http://amrita.dgplug.org/?p=57</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Durga Puja, the most awaited festival in the life of the bengalis&amp;#8217;, is almost over now&amp;#8230;but still our heart and mind both craves to get involved in the exulted colours of this festival&amp;#8230;it rejuvenates our mind, revitalise our souls and enliven our spirits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its the best time to reconnect with our friends and relatives and reciprocate our plethora of stories&amp;#8230;its time now again to indulge ourselves in our tedious schedules but with lots of positive feeling &lt;img src=&quot;http://amrita.dgplug.org/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; class=&quot;wp-smiley&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-10-09T07:25:43+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://archu.wordpress.com/?p=762">
	<title>Archu's Cyberspace...!: archu</title>
	<link>http://archu.wordpress.com/2011/09/29/shade-share-help-and-adore/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Its been a pleasure all the way to be associated with SHADE group, for the past 3 years. Though I keep track of the activities and try to contribute whenever I can. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is an initiative started by a fellow IT employee named Raghavan. He collects whatever amount which is possible to contribute by his friends, family, colleagues each month and donate to a social cause. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://shade.org.in/InitialMailAboutShade.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;initial announcement &lt;/a&gt;regarding this group was sent by him, gathered interest among the like minded people. Now the group does many activities like supporting some NGOs, orphanages, etc as and when need arises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please visit the &lt;a href=&quot;http://shade.org.in/index-old.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SHADE website&lt;/a&gt; to know more. They have their presence in both google groups and facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I like about this group is transactions are transparent and contributions reaches the expected deprieved people in time. I wish them good luck in their initiative &lt;img src=&quot;http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; class=&quot;wp-smiley&quot; /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/archu.wordpress.com/762/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/archu.wordpress.com/762/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=archu.wordpress.com&amp;#038;blog=373911&amp;#038;post=762&amp;#038;subd=archu&amp;#038;ref=&amp;#038;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-09-29T12:50:49+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://barkha.in/blog/?p=160">
	<title>Certified crazy: Tiramisu  check</title>
	<link>http://barkha.in/blog/2011/08/20/tiramisu-check/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Another todo item ticked off. Tiramisu has been made. So what if it took longer to find Marsala at Carrefour Antibes than to actually make tiramisu? Pics shall be uploaded tomorrow once it is served. (Right now bites have started to go missing from the container cooling in the fridge) &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-08-20T20:58:47+00:00</dc:date>
	<dc:creator>barkha</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://barkha.in/blog/2011/08/17/test-post-from-the-iphone-app/">
	<title>Certified crazy: Test post from the iPhone app</title>
	<link>http://barkha.in/blog/2011/08/17/test-post-from-the-iphone-app/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Looks ok. Would suffice (hopefully) the need of writing a few words per day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, tonight&amp;#8217;s todo: make bruschetta and install wp touch plugin. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-08-17T12:25:13+00:00</dc:date>
	<dc:creator>barkha</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://barkha.in/blog/?p=155">
	<title>Certified crazy: The Rome trip</title>
	<link>http://barkha.in/blog/2011/08/17/the-rome-trip/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Some months ago, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/sankarshan&quot;&gt;@sankarshan &lt;/a&gt;and &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/runa_b&quot;&gt;@runa_b&lt;/a&gt; planned a trip around Europe. &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/aanjhan&quot;&gt;@aanjhan &lt;/a&gt;from swiss, along with the couple met up at Rome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some awesome food, great conversation and a lot of fun was had. Some pictures are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/barkha/sets/72157626988441629/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;uploaded&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is one of my favorite pictures from the set: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/barkha/5896365725/&quot; title=&quot;The colosseum by barkha, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5196/5896365725_6af999a6e2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;332&quot; alt=&quot;The colosseum&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-08-17T11:34:05+00:00</dc:date>
	<dc:creator>barkha</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://opensourcebuzz.technetra.com/?p=434">
	<title>Open Source Buzz: OSCON 2011 this week</title>
	<link>http://opensourcebuzz.technetra.com/2011/07/25/oscon-2011-this-week/</link>
	<content:encoded>OSCON 2011 starts off this week on Wednesday July 27th with keynotes by Jono Bacon from Ubuntu, Jim Zemlin of the Linux Foundation and Karen Sandler of GNOME Foundation. Through the week, OSCON also brings some excellent topics on open source in mobile, education, cloud as well as open source tools and technologies including PHP, [...]</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-07-26T06:11:23+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://archu.wordpress.com/?p=758">
	<title>Archu's Cyberspace...!: archu</title>
	<link>http://archu.wordpress.com/2011/07/16/after-a-long-time-3/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Yes really a long time indeed..&lt;br /&gt;
Not sure why it took so long. I wont blame &amp;#8220;No Time&amp;#8221; as everyone else does..&lt;br /&gt;
I guess I just give it some time..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being in the start and middle of the weekend is really a nice feeling..&lt;br /&gt;
Hope the saturdays are never ending!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/archu.wordpress.com/758/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/archu.wordpress.com/758/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=archu.wordpress.com&amp;#038;blog=373911&amp;#038;post=758&amp;#038;subd=archu&amp;#038;ref=&amp;#038;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-07-16T17:33:12+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:md5:584d88d40ebfb33b1ea1295b8687356f">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: E-filing IncomeTax returns in india</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2011/E-filing-IncomeTax-returns-in-india</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The Indian government agency that runs the Income-Tax portal  &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in&quot;&gt;incometaxindiaefiling.gov.in&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; has
very thoughtfully provided an electronic filing facility for its citizens which
enables all tax-payers to file their Tax returns without a trip to the local
Income Tax Office. However, their thoughtfulness only extends to Windows users
as they have provided the e-forms only in the MSOffice .xls format which will
not run any macros on a non-Windows platform. Now, I have not used Windows for
many years now and having been forced to pay for a half-baked edition
pre-installed on my laptop, I could not wait for my warranty to finish and free
up that disk space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, I found two Open-Office hacks for the ITR forms 1 and 2 at:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;viewer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kseboa.org/download/utilities.html&quot;&gt;http://www.kseboa.org/download/utilities.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://freedom-matters.in&quot; href=&quot;http://freedom-matters.in/&quot; class=&quot;externalLink&quot;&gt;http://freedom-matters.in&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
However, the Open-Office  supported &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kseboa.org/download/utilities.html&quot;&gt;ITR-2 form from KSEB&lt;/a&gt; is
borked -- has locked cells which will not work nor retrieve macros in
Open-Office and many fields and cells are protected, making it impossible to
enter data so that the Tax macros work properly. The ITR-2 form (available from
the above link) has some errors in the conversion for Open Office --In Part B -
TI in Computation of total income. It does not allow you to enter any figures
in the following fields:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
1. Salaries (6 of Schedule S)&lt;br /&gt;
2. Income from house property (C of Schedule-HP) (Enter nil if loss)&lt;br /&gt;
3. Capital gains&lt;br /&gt;
4. Income from other sources&lt;br /&gt;
This prevents the macro from tabulating the Total (Example: A + B +Total of (I)
for all fields), due to which its not possible to tabulate the final tax
payable.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Does anyone know how to get locked cell macros to work in Open-Office? All help
and pointers to get these hacks working on Open-Office would be a big help.
TIA.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
PS: FWIW, I had asked this question on the local LUG list, which was a waste as
&lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/ilug-bengaluru/browse_thread/thread/1aea82c72a377e3?hl=en&quot; class=&quot;ot-anchor&quot;&gt;one list member, who didnt read the question, chose to focus
his undivided attention on the terrible mistake I made -- used the word 
'company'&lt;/a&gt;. Thereafter, it was a fun exercise in
&amp;quot;I-am-the-loudest-jerk-and-bully-here&amp;quot; ad hominem and logical fallacies. Yeah,
total WIN on the technical help scale. The smartz knocked my socks
off! &lt;br /&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-07-13T12:01:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://barkha.in/blog/?p=151">
	<title>Certified crazy: Long time, blog!</title>
	<link>http://barkha.in/blog/2011/06/17/long-time-blog/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Long, long time ago, there used to be a girl who wrote a blog, thought out delicate sentences and framed out words, weaved them with the events in her life, and hit the publish button with a smile on her face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, she finds no excitement to blog, nothing to say to the big world out there. She has heard that sometimes, this phenomenon hits other people too, but she fears this is something that she won&amp;#8217;t recover from, anytime soon, if she does, that is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give her a few good reasons to keep this blog going. She&amp;#8217;ll be happy, I know.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-06-17T14:35:36+00:00</dc:date>
	<dc:creator>barkha</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:md5:4dd38721281663fbbd4ea514c80ae69e">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: TiddlyWiki</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2011/TiddlyWiki</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I've been using &lt;a href=&quot;http://tiddlywiki.com&quot;&gt;TiddlyWiki&lt;/a&gt; for some
years as a personal wiki space and although the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tiddlywiki.com/firstversion.html&quot;&gt;first version&lt;/a&gt; was a bit
clumsy about saving and searching ; today, it is the most re-usable, portable,
easily shared self-contained wiki that you can find to manage your local tasks
and information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mainly, I use TiddlyWiki to maintain notes, store and manage links. While
there are online sites like Delicious and Stumbleupon which facilitate users
sharing weblinks, they dont have the highly customizable features that
Tiddlywiki has ; namely, the freedom to customize, edit pages and add oodles of
content (ex. store phone nos, or other personal data which you dont want to
store on a public space). Sometimes, I want to add IRC conversation snippets or
installation notes as a future reference for something I had tried previously
and found useful and it makes it very easy to add new tiddlers instantly. This
level of fine-grained user-level customization is not available in any online
site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to share this so that folks who like wikis for the ease of editing
can use Tiddlywiki instead of struggling to maintain local wiki installations
on their servers. Dont forget that Tiddlywiki is the only wiki that does not
need a server-side implementation and runs entirely on your browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TiddlyWiki is built on a combination of HTML, CSS and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JavaScript&quot;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/a&gt; and you can start by
downloading an empty.html page to start using it. Here is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://svn.tiddlywiki.org/&quot;&gt;sourcecode&lt;/a&gt; if you want to contribute new
features, and they also have a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tiddlywiki.org/&quot;&gt;community
space&lt;/a&gt;, some tutorials, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://trac.tiddlywiki.org/&quot;&gt;bug
tracker&lt;/a&gt;, and many freely available themes to customize your local wikipage.
In short, the uses are as (un)limited as your imagination is. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-06-13T06:24:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://opensourcebuzz.technetra.com/?p=432">
	<title>Open Source Buzz: Apache Software Foundation inherits OpenOffice.org code base</title>
	<link>http://opensourcebuzz.technetra.com/2011/06/01/apache-software-foundation-inherits-openofficeorg-code-base/</link>
	<content:encoded>A giant step in the right direction in the open source world&amp;#8230;. Finally Oracle has donated OpenOffice.org&amp;#8217;s code base to the Apache Software Foundation.
Interesting comments by Steven Vaughan-Nichols.</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-06-02T03:27:47+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:md5:84590c44fbcb98115873bd03ecbf0ccd">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: buying LIC Jeevan Dukh insurance policy from L&amp;T Finance</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2011/buying-LIC-Jeevan-Dukh-insurance-policy-from-LT-Finance</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ltfinance.com/&quot;&gt;L&amp;amp;T Finance, Bangalore&lt;/a&gt;, sells
personalized financial solutions, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ltfinance.com/insurance-and-mutual-funds.aspx&quot;&gt;LIC's life insurance
policies&lt;/a&gt; to retail customers and a very pushy marketing person managed to
hound us since last year until we finally succumbed into buying a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.licindia.in/endowment_005_features.htm&quot;&gt;Jeevan Anand insurance
policy&lt;/a&gt;. Little did we know that instead of 'Anand' (joy) it would be the
beginning of a period of &amp;quot;Dukh&amp;quot; (sadness) -- after the INR 54,157/- cheque was
encashed by them, the sales agent says there would be a medical test and their
office would call us to schedule it. WTH?
&lt;p&gt;Thereafter, S.I.L.E.N.C.E.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The silence lasted for two months as the sales agent at the Bangalore office
would not take our calls nor did he call us back with details of when the
medical test would be scheduled -- So why did the sales guy NOT mention an
important detail like a &amp;quot;medical test&amp;quot; BEFORE taking the INR. 54,157/- cheque
when he knew it was a &lt;strong&gt;senior citizen&lt;/strong&gt; taking the policy, nor
was this mentioned during the zillion phone calls when he wanted to sell the
policy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More S.I.L.E.N.C.E.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some hassle, we got the Bangalore office number and it was our duty to
keep calling them to find out the status of our policy. Finally, we heard that
the sales agent had left their employment, talk to a manager --Err..what
happened to the &lt;strong&gt;INR. 54,157/- cheque that L&amp;amp;T had encashed on
02-Feb-2011&lt;/strong&gt; --were they going to return the money to us or grant the
Jeevan Anand policy? Nobody at the L&amp;amp;T Finance office in Bangalore knew who
was handling the case, atleast that is what we were told upon repeatedly
calling them, being shunted around to speak to different employees, and after
many weeks of excuses and false assurances it took them only TWO months to
schedule the first medical test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medical done, we still had no idea if they were actually going to issue a
policy, or not. More silence followed and a week of calling them incessantly
(the bane of mobile phones and people not picking your calls) were told that
the medical test results would go to the L&amp;amp;T Hyderabad office which would
make a decision. Upon more calls from us (the L&amp;amp;T Finance Bangalore
employees just dont bother to inform us of the policy status) we were told that
there would be another medical test....wait, did the Bangalore office realize
this TWO months after the first medical test? That they would need to
reschedule the second medical test and we were supposed to await a call (which
would never come) informing us when to go for the test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Days have passed, but there was no call, only S.I.L.E.N.C.E for company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, we called the local L&amp;amp;T Finance employee -- if they dont wish
to schedule the second medical test and make a decision regarding the health
eligibility, the least they could do was to return the money. Instead, we were
given the excuse that it was the Hyderabad office making the decision and their
local Bangalore office was just collecting documents and couriering it to
Hyderabad for final decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&amp;amp;T Finance, if you dont intend to give the LIC Jeevan Anand policy, the
least you can do is return the 54,157/- Rupees that you encashed FOUR months
ago. Is this the way you treat senior citizens, by keeping their money in
limbo, without interest for FOUR months while you take your own sweet time to
make a decision? Is this is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ltfinance.com/insurance-and-mutual-funds.aspx&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;emphasis on
systematic and planned investments&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; service L&amp;amp;T Finance provides? Why
do the L&amp;amp;T Finance sales agent NOT mention important deal-breakers like a
&amp;quot;medical tests&amp;quot; BEFORE encashing the INR.54,157/- cheque or during the zillion
phone calls when they hound you to sell their insurance policies --or is that
also a part of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ltfinance.com/insurance-and-mutual-funds.aspx&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;continuous
monitoring and active re-balancing depending on changing needs and market
dynamics&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; service that LT sales agents use to divest the senior citizens of
their life-savings? I wonder how many other senior citizens have paid you their
hard-earned money for which you dont pay any interest whatsoever, while taking
half a year to make a simple decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had always thought that L&amp;amp;T was a respectable brand name and enjoyed
so much goodwill that I would have trusted them blindly BUT the L&amp;amp;T Finance
employees have managed to destroy the enormous goodwill that the company
enjoyed. Being a Finance company they would know that had this amount been
invested in the simplest investment plan in any government bank's fixed deposit
scheme, it would have earned around 10% interest for the last half year.
&lt;strong&gt;Shame on you L&amp;amp;T Finance --do the math and return INR. 54,157/-
with interest if you are not interested in allotting the Jeevan Anand policy
immediately!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE [2011may28]&lt;/strong&gt;:: Others personal experience and public
opinions on LIC's Jeevan Anand policy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vinayahs.com/archives/2011/01/18/how-to-surrender-and-close-your-lic-jeevan-anand-life-insurance-policy/&quot;&gt;
http://www.vinayahs.com/archives/2011/01/18/how-to-surrender-and-close-your-lic-jeevan-anand-life-insurance-policy/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

[1] &lt;a href=&quot;http://hubpages.com/hub/MY-VIEW-ON-LICS-JEEVAN-ANAND&quot;&gt;http://hubpages.com/hub/MY-VIEW-ON-LICS-JEEVAN-ANAND&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

[2] &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mouthshut.com/product-reviews/Jeevan-Anand-925037407&quot;&gt;http://www.mouthshut.com/product-reviews/Jeevan-Anand-925037407&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

[3] &lt;a href=&quot;http://ritusays.wordpress.com/2011/01/21/lic-life-insurance-corporation-of-india-jeevan-anand-endowment-assurance-and-life-insurance-policy/&quot;&gt;
http://ritusays.wordpress.com/2011/01/21/lic-life-insurance-corporation-of-india-jeevan-anand-endowment-assurance-and-life-insurance-policy/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

[4] &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.r2iclubforums.com/forums/showthread.php/20963-LIC-Jeevan-Anand-1&quot;&gt;http://www.r2iclubforums.com/forums/showthread.php/20963-LIC-Jeevan-Anand-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.r2iclubforums.com/forums/showthread.php/20963-LIC-Jeevan-Anand-1&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE [2011jun30]&lt;/strong&gt;:: Soon after this blog was published,
the L&amp;amp;T company representative contacted us and quickly arranged for the
second test but a few days after that they were still unable to tell if LIC
would issue the policy or not. The LIC agent also contacted us and they came up
with a new scheme to enroll in (read, which entails us spending more on
premiums with very little to show in terms of returns). In all it sounded like
a terrible bargain and we insisted they return the 54,157/- Rupees without
interest. There was some back-and-forth and we finally decided that if they
didnt return the money (we were not even asking for the 6 months of interest at
10%), we would go the legal route where we would claim interest and harassment
damages. LIC decided to return the money and we got the check this week. End of
story.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-05-28T04:29:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://netra.wordpress.com/?p=420">
	<title>Netra's Weblog: Netra</title>
	<link>http://netra.wordpress.com/2011/05/26/indescribable/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;ನಿನಗಾಗಿ&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ನಿನ್ನ ಒಲುಮೆಯ ಬೆಳಕಲ್ಲಿ ಬಾಳಾಗಿದೆ ನಂದನ&lt;br /&gt;
ಪ್ರತಿ ಕ್ಷಣವೂ ಮಿಡಿಯುತಿದೆ ನಿನಗಾಗಿ ಈ ಮನ&lt;br /&gt;
ಭಾವದೆಲ್ಲೆಯ ಮೀರಿದ ಭಾವ ಪ್ರೀತಿ ಸೀಮೆಯ ದಾಟಿದ ಪ್ರೀತಿ&lt;br /&gt;
ನಿನ್ನ ಪ್ರೇರಣೆಯಲ್ಲವೇ ಪ್ರೇಮದ ಈ ರೀತಿ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-ನೇತ್ರಾ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/netra.wordpress.com/420/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/netra.wordpress.com/420/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/netra.wordpress.com/420/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/netra.wordpress.com/420/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/netra.wordpress.com/420/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/netra.wordpress.com/420/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/netra.wordpress.com/420/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/netra.wordpress.com/420/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/netra.wordpress.com/420/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/netra.wordpress.com/420/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/netra.wordpress.com/420/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/netra.wordpress.com/420/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/netra.wordpress.com/420/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/netra.wordpress.com/420/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=netra.wordpress.com&amp;#038;blog=2323676&amp;#038;post=420&amp;#038;subd=netra&amp;#038;ref=&amp;#038;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-05-26T07:26:03+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:md5:b584848b96a6a38f2e3e3c76b55eaab8">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: Building packages from source tutorial by DebianWomen</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2011/Building-packages-from-source-tutorial-by-DebianWomen</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;DW is conducting a packaging tutorial. Do note, this is not a tutorial for
upstream package building from source, but still, its worth listening to. Here
is Marga's announcement::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you enthusiastic about Debian and thinking about contributing? We want
to guide you with the basics.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We are convinced that there are a lot of people out there that want to get
involved with Free Software but don't know where to start.  For Debian,
the most common task you'll do as a contributor is rebuilding a package.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Debian Women project, in collaboration with the OpenHatch project, will be
holding an IRC event to help people that want to compile their first Debian
package from source, and apply their first patch.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ins&gt;The event&lt;/ins&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
On Saturday May 7th, two tutorial sessions will be held on #debian-women on
&lt;a href=&quot;http://irc.debian.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;irc.debian.org&lt;/a&gt; to help
people rebuild a package for the first time.&lt;br /&gt;
The earlier session, suggested for those that live in Oceania, Asia, Africa and
Europe, will be held at 11:00 UTC. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The later session, suggested for those that live in the Americas, will be
held at 22:00 UTC. You can find out the exact time in your timezone by using
the timezone converter: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.timezoneconverter.com/cgi-bin/tzc.tzc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.timezoneconverter.com/cgi-bin/tzc.tzc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There will be people available to answer questions and generally help out with
any difficulties that might arise all along the day.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
More info at &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.debian.org/DebianWomen/BuildItEvent&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://wiki.debian.org/DebianWomen/BuildItEvent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ins&gt;Intended audience&lt;/ins&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This event is aimed to anyone who wants to rebuild a Debian package for the
first time, it's a simple task that doesn't require any previous knowledge,
only a working installation of Debian (or Ubuntu, or other Debian-derived
system).  We want to particularly encourage women who want to get
involved, to take their first steps in&lt;br /&gt;
contributing to Free Software, but everybody is welcome.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ins&gt;More about IRC&lt;/ins&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
IRC is a real-time chat system you can use to get in touch with members of the
Debian community. You can connect to IRC through lots of different clients,
including xchat, pidgin and konversation.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ins&gt;About Debian Women&lt;/ins&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Debian Women project seeks to balance and diversify the Debian Project by
actively engaging with interested women and encouraging them to become more
involved with Debian. &lt;a href=&quot;http://women.debian.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://women.debian.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ins&gt;About OpenHatch&lt;/ins&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
OpenHatch is an open source community aiming to help newcomers find their way
into free software projects. It works towards this goal through on-line and
outreach events. This event is a reappropriation of the OpenHatch &amp;quot;Build it&amp;quot;
events.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
--&lt;br /&gt;
Besos,&lt;br /&gt;
Marga&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-05-03T04:15:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:md5:4bcc1f64fdc58e0dd2dadc25a13431c1">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: Internet free speech meme-&quot;Casteism can get you jailed but Sexism and Ageism are acceptable in Indian politics&quot;</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2011/Internet-free-speech-meme-%22Casteism-can-get-you-jailed-but-Sexism-and-Ageism-are-acceptable-in-Indian-politics%22</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I avoid meme's but had to rethink my stance after the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2011/04/28/technology/28internet.html?partner=rss&amp;amp;emc=rss&quot;&gt;
Information Technology Rules, 2011, (aka the Electronic Service Delivery)
Act&lt;/a&gt; was quietly implemented last month. This Act states that any content
that is &amp;quot;threatening to the unity, integrity, defense, security or sovereignty
of India, friendly relations with foreign states or public order, including any
content on the web that is blasphemous, scandalous, defames, or can be
considered obscene&amp;quot;, eligible for immediate removal by the hosting provider
upon order from the Department of Information and Technology. Now, that was the
long-winded legalese which is so darn vague but here is the short version: &amp;quot;you
cannot criticize politicians publicly, ever.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such draconian censorship rules have no place in a democracy that values
free-speech and this calls for a  free speech meme -- I'm reproducing
content (with author credits) from other websites which criticizes politicians
on my blog, making it harder for DIT/gov.in to implement censorship
successfully. For starters, Antara Sen criticizing the Communists for
encouraging Sexism and Ageism in Indian politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;print-title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.asianage.com/print/70982&quot;&gt;The
politics of respect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Antara Dev Sen , Created 30 Apr 2011 - 00:00&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Which is worse — calling one of our finest politicians and a respected elder
statesman a mummified corpse, a dead man who has no business opening his mouth?
Or saying that the spirited woman leader and challenger to the Communist throne
of Bengal ignores funds from Bengaluru to get money from the United States,
much like bazaar women forget smaller clients when they get bigger patrons?
Going by the collective shock and horror, the latter comment wins hands
down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
What? He called her a prostitute? Do they stop at nothing? Veteran Communist
Party of India-Marxist (CPI-M) leader and member of Parliament Anil Basu was
promptly pilloried by all concerned, including his own party members. West
Bengal chief minister Buddhadeb Bhattacharjee apologised publicly, censured Mr
Basu and pulled him out of campaigning. What he had said was uncivilised and
unbecoming of a Communist, lamented the mortified chief minister. It was
unpardonable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
True. Mr Basu had used shocking language and imagery, suggesting (thanks to the
blinding hatred for the US that Communists have) that the US was Mamata
Banerjee’s “bhaataar” (slang for a woman’s keeper) now, so she didn’t have to
look at smaller homegrown patrons in Bengaluru, Chennai or Andhra Pradesh. Like
the women of Sonagachhi (Kolkata’s red light district), she had dumped smaller
babus for bigger ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Now, I hate to break this to our slanderous comrade and gentlefolk horrified by
the insult, but moving from smaller to bigger clients is not the business
strategy of prostitutes alone. It’s common sense. It happens in all
professional and business dealings, in all societies and in all times. So Mr
Basu’s sex-worker imagery was not about the logic of fund-raising — it was
about using degrading stereotypes to insult a woman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This jibe shows how regressively patriarchal even our Communist bastion is. Sex
workers can be invoked as an insult in a state that came to power professing to
fight for workers’ rights and dignity of labour and clung to power for more
than three decades with the muscle provided by lowly workers of all kinds.
Could the comrade have made similar derogatory allusions to low-caste tanners
or to Doms who burn corpses? Perhaps not. But chastity is such a deep need of
Indian patriarchy that even a seasoned Communist can snigger at sex workers.
They aren’t really workers, just fallen women. More than Ms Banerjee, it is
prostitutes who have been insulted here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
But the intent was to hit out at the deviant woman who dared to challenge the
status quo. And this is not the first time that Ms Banerjee — herself adept at
insult — has been attacked with sexist tools. During the Singur agitation, when
she was busy taking our breath away with her astounding dramatics, this same Mr
Basu had declared that if he had his way he would have dragged her by her hair
and plonked her back home instead of allowing her to sit in dharnas. Clearly,
for this little caveman in a dhoti, home is where the woman belongs. Not on the
streets or in sit-ins. Not in politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In fact, the cunning Trinamul Congress chief has been called “brain dead” by
the Communists — an accusation so far from the truth that it makes you wonder
whether the Communists have completely lost their minds. And when Ms Banerjee
first came up with her slogan “Ma, maati, maanush!” (mother, earth, people)
some Left leaders had sniggered, “But she isn’t a mother — what does she know
of motherhood?” In a patriarchal society, the good woman is domesticated and
acceptable as a wife, a mother, a daughter-in-law. But if you are an unmarried
politician woman — gosh, you have a problem, sister! You don’t fit in, you are
hugely inadequate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
And it is not always men who point out this inadequacy. Some time ago, the
feisty Renuka Chowdhury, then minister for women and child development, had hit
out at Mayawati on the Aarushi Talwar murder case. She herself was thinking as
a mother, she announced righteously, but Ms Mayawati was not a mother, she
could only think as a chief minister. And was therefore wrong, of course.
Shortly thereafter, Maneka Gandhi was not allowed to flout rules to meet her
son Varun in a Uttar Pradesh jail. Ms Mayawati is not a mother, Ms Gandhi hit
back, how could she understand a mother’s concerns?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Ages ago, a young Indira Gandhi was called a “goongi gudiya” (a dumb doll) by
her respectable opponents. When she grew to become the most powerful Prime
Minister India ever had, she was lauded as “the only man in her Cabinet”.
Patriarchal symbolism plays a vital role in our perception of political
leaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The wife, widow or daughter-in-law is very readily acceptable, and most of our
women leaders play that role beautifully. And those who don’t — like the
unmarried Ms Mayawati or Ms Banerjee — have many extra battles to fight. One
way of sidestepping this is to become the universal mother, like “Amma”
Jayalalithaa. But the “Behenji” or the “Didi” can only be stereotyped as a dry,
heartless, careerist old maid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
But plugging into derogatory stereotypes has been part of the game of politics.
What I find alarming is our refusal to see such insults when they are not
included in the high-profile, politicised identity groups. Casteism in poll
campaigns can get you jailed. Sexism is appalling and can get you in trouble.
But ageism, however mean and hurtful, is acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Which is why I am shocked at the jibe of Bratya Basu, theatreperson and
Trinamul Congress candidate in West Bengal, at Somnath Chatterjee. The former
Lok Sabha Speaker, though expelled from the CPI(M) for putting the Indian
Constitution before the party during the confidence vote, had generously agreed
to canvass for CPI(M) minister Gautam Deb. Quick as a flash, Mr Bratya Basu —
the challenger in the minister’s constituency, the “intellectual” and
first-time politician — attacked the elder statesman, calling him a mummified
corpse out of a coffin. Why should anyone listen to him?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Egyptian mummy, he grimaced for effect, why is he talking in Bengali? He
should talk in hieroglyphics!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe civil campaigning is indeed the language of the dead. Maybe lumpenised
politics does not need informed debate — either on the campaign trail or in
Parliament, the highest seat of rowdy ruckus. Our democracy can just ride on
vulgar name-calling and derogatory stereotypes. The vulgarisation of politics
has bred a new language for a new age of ungracious, uncivil, illiberal
politicians. And unless they are checked, this crude lot will breathe their own
mean spirit into our wounded democracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Antara Dev Sen is editor of The Little Magazine. She can be contacted
at: sen@littlemag.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-04-30T04:37:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:md5:11c2984e73e08452c926a512fb3ec38a">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: Vidalia calling volunteers</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2011/Vidalia-calling-volunteers</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://openhatch.org&quot;&gt;Openhatch&lt;/a&gt; is holding a 'build it'
initiative in collaboration with &lt;a href=&quot;http://torproject.org&quot;&gt;Vidalia&lt;/a&gt;
which is the front-end for the proxy you installed on your system. Most
importantly, for a change, has India-friendly timings instead of a graveyard
shift(s) which make it hard for non-owls (like me) to attend meetings. So, if
you have C/C++ skills, dont forget to join &lt;a href=&quot;http://chat.mibbit.com/?server=irc.oftc.net&amp;amp;channel=%23vidalia&quot;&gt;#vidalia
on irc.oftc.net&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/converted.html?day=15&amp;amp;month=4&amp;amp;year=2011&amp;amp;hour=13&amp;amp;min=0&amp;amp;sec=0&amp;amp;p1=0&amp;amp;p2=44&quot;&gt;
18:30 hrs, today&lt;/a&gt; and volunteer! Continue reading for more details from,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.torproject.org/blog/vidalia-get-involved&quot;&gt;https://blog.torproject.org/blog/vidalia-get-involved&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone, for those who don't know me, I'm the one that's taking care
of Vidalia these days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other day I was contacted by paulproteus in the #vidalia IRC channel
about an initiative they (OpenHatch) are organizing called &amp;quot;Build It&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The idea&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open Source projects live and die depending on contributors and people that
want to see the project evolve, but this isn't so easy sometimes. The guys
behind the Build It initiative have a theory about this difficulty:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;...lots of users of free desktop software want to get involved in
customizing or contributing to the project's development, but they haven't
gotten to the first step of getting the program to compile.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I'm a Gentoo user for years now, the compilation part comes naturally
to me and I haven't thought of this issue that way but it's an interesting
approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The event&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, people involved in Vidalia and other Open Source projects will be
at a specific time online to help users (future developers, may be &lt;img src=&quot;http://svaksha.com/themes/default/smilies/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; class=&quot;smiley&quot; /&gt; ) jump
over this compilation wall. Particularly, Vidalia is scheduled for this Friday
at 13:00 UTC in the same place as usual: #vidalia at OFTC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this event is taking place on a particular day and a particular time,
I'm online all the time (even when I'm not in front of the computer). So if you
want to contribute to Vidalia or any of the projects around Tor (or Tor
itself), don't hesitate, just get online and start typing, but be patient and
stick around. Also, you'd probably want to read this: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/getinvolved/volunteer.html.en&quot; title=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/getinvolved/volunteer.html.en&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.torproject.org/getinvolved/volunteer.html.en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to know more about the Buld It initiative, you can ask in
#openhatch at Freenode, or read here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://openhatch.org/wiki/Build_it&quot; title=&quot;https://openhatch.org/wiki/Build_it&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://openhatch.org/wiki/Build_it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-04-15T05:39:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:md5:95fac4245258de0bbfe9bb2906a88991">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: b0rked Broadcom bcm43xx drivers</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2011/b0rked-Broadcom-bcm43xx-drivers</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;strong&gt;Dear Broadcom&lt;/strong&gt;, Despite your late gesture of opensourcing the
bcm43xx wireless drivers, I continue to have issues -- Last week a kernel
upgrade from lucid not only broke the driver but managed to kill the nvidia
drivers for good measure -- it was easier to take a data backup and do a clean
re-installation of Lucid than waste a lot of time figuring out how your bcm43xx
driver broke the nvidia drivers killing my graphics display
totally. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, I was mistaken about it being a kernel upgrade (to 2.6.35) issue as
the peace lasted for hardly 3 days -- since I am blessed with having to start
my monday morning troubleshooting your broken hardware drivers (on 2.6.32-21
generic kernel version) instead of getting actual work done.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;lucid@ubuntu:~$ dpkg --list |grep b43&lt;br /&gt;
ii 
b43-fwcutter            
1:012-1build1          Utility for
extracting Broadcom 43xx firmwar&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;lucid@ubuntu:~$ dpkg --list |grep bcmwl&lt;br /&gt;
ii  bcmwl-modaliases      
5.60.48.36+bdcom-0ubuntu3       Modaliases for
the Broadcom 802.11 Linux STA&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
So the &amp;quot;b43-fwcutter&amp;quot; utility package exists on my system (as I had installed
and activated the drivers) but something between each reboot was blocking the
drivers as the link would suddenly be hard blocked. This despite me taking the
trouble to NOT upgrade from the 2.6.32-21 generic kernel version.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Then, I checked the B43 blacklisted file:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;lucid@ubuntu:~$ cat /etc/modprobe.d/* | egrep
'8180|acx|at76|ath|b43|bcm|CX|eth|ipw|irmware|isl|lbtf|orinoco|ndiswrapper|NPE|p54|prism|rtl|rt2|rt3|rt6|rt7|witch|wl'&lt;br /&gt;

# which ath5k cannot recover. To prevent this condition, stop&lt;br /&gt;
blacklist ath_pci&lt;br /&gt;
blacklist eth1394&lt;br /&gt;
# replaced by p54pci&lt;br /&gt;
blacklist prism54&lt;br /&gt;
# replaced by b43 and ssb.&lt;br /&gt;
blacklist bcm43xx&lt;br /&gt;
blacklist uart6850&lt;br /&gt;
blacklist twl4030_wdt&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;and sure enough, &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;bcm43xx&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; was indeed on the
blacklist.....nice, girdle up for more yakshaving!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Next, I paid a visit to the &amp;quot;blacklist.conf&amp;quot; file and commented out the line
&amp;quot;blacklist bcm43xx&amp;quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Rebooted for it to take effect. Nada, Zilch, still no wifi.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;lucid@ubuntu:/lib/firmware/b43$ ls&lt;br /&gt;
a0g0bsinitvals5.fw  a0g1bsinitvals13.fw 
a0g1initvals5.fw     b0g0bsinitvals9.fw 
lp0bsinitvals13.fw  lp0initvals14.fw   
n0initvals11.fw  ucode14.fw&lt;br /&gt;
a0g0bsinitvals9.fw  a0g1bsinitvals5.fw  
a0g1initvals9.fw     b0g0initvals13.fw  
lp0bsinitvals14.fw  lp0initvals15.fw   
pcm5.fw          ucode15.fw&lt;br /&gt;
a0g0initvals5.fw    a0g1bsinitvals9.fw  
b0g0bsinitvals13.fw  b0g0initvals5.fw   
lp0bsinitvals15.fw  n0absinitvals11.fw 
ucode11.fw       ucode5.fw&lt;br /&gt;
a0g0initvals9.fw    a0g1initvals13.fw   
b0g0bsinitvals5.fw   b0g0initvals9.fw   
lp0initvals13.fw    n0bsinitvals11.fw  
ucode13.fw       ucode9.fw&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;lucid@ubuntu:~$ cd /lib/firmware/brcm&lt;br /&gt;
bash: cd: /lib/firmware/brcm: No such file or directory&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Then, a &lt;code&gt;sudo ln -s bcm43xx-0-610-809-0.fw bcm43xx-0.fw&lt;/code&gt; and
&lt;code&gt;sudo ln -s bcm43xx_hdr-0-610-809-0.fw bcm43xx_hdr-0.fw&lt;/code&gt; should have
loaded and activated the drivers after a reboot. It did not, forcing me to
switch to a wired connection on a laptop. WTF!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Broadcom&lt;/strong&gt;, fiddling with &amp;quot;bcm43xx&amp;quot; is a sure-fire way to kill
time. Thankyou very much for the Yak-shaving experience --it serves as a
constant reminder to me, why I &lt;strong&gt;will&lt;/strong&gt; never (unknowingly) buy
another Broadcom driven product in future, ever! KTHXBAI.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ins&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;:: Its a &amp;quot;networking disabled on boot&amp;quot; bug in
Ubuntu-Lucid and Maverick that has a fix (but not yet committed for
Maverick):&lt;br /&gt;
[0] &lt;a href=&quot;http://ubuntuforums.org/showthread.php?t=1594577&quot;&gt;http://ubuntuforums.org/showthread.php?t=1594577&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

[1] &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/network-manager/+bug/524454&quot;&gt;https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/network-manager/+bug/524454&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

[2] &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.ubuntu.com/community/WifiDocs/Driver/bcm43xx#Installing%20b43%20drivers&quot;&gt;
https://help.ubuntu.com/community/WifiDocs/Driver/bcm43xx#Installing%20b43%20drivers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

[3] &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qc4blog.com/?p=857&quot;&gt;http://www.qc4blog.com/?p=857&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I've tried everything mentioned in the above threads to no avail. Wifi is out
cold!&lt;br /&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-04-04T04:28:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3835450307118836937.post-5359240188621531554">
	<title>All things technical...: mavu.in</title>
	<link>http://meworkstoo.blogspot.com/2011/03/mavuin.html</link>
	<content:encoded>Hi All,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My blog has a new &lt;a href=&quot;http://mavu.in/&quot;&gt;home&lt;/a&gt;. I've had the domain for quite sometime and I finally decided I'm going to move and be active. See y'all there!&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/3835450307118836937-5359240188621531554?l=meworkstoo.blogspot.com&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-03-15T14:11:38+00:00</dc:date>
	<dc:creator>satya</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:md5:bd68364f1eca2977a3342b99d8adb5d0">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: mukta Aruna Ramchandra Shanbhag</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2011/mukta-Aruna-Ramchandra-Shanbhag</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow the the world will celebrate the 100th International Women's Day,
but today the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.voanews.com/english/news/asia/India-High-Court-Rules-On-Euthanasia-117513383.html&quot;&gt;
Supreme Court verdict&lt;/a&gt; rejected the mercy-killing petition of &lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/wiki/Aruna_shanbhag&quot;&gt;Aruna
Ramchandra Shanbhag&lt;/a&gt;, filed by Pinky Virani the author of &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.indianexpress.com/res/web/pIe/ie/daily/19980602/15351154.html&quot;&gt;Aruna's
Story&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;. In a country like India, &amp;quot;mercy killing&amp;quot; (whether passive or not)
will definitely be misused by parties with vested interests and while I welcome
the court's judgement on passive euthanasia, I can't help but wonder if India
has done enough since then. As Usha writes, &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://agelessbonding.blogspot.com/2008/03/rape-and-dishonour.html&quot;&gt;In the 60s
, Jayakantan wrote a story called “Agnipravesam” where a college girl is raped
in a car on a dark rainy evening . On seeing her state when she reaches home,
her poor widowed mother immediately senses what has happened. She takes her in
and simply pours water on the girls head; then she tells her to treat the water
as fire and feel pure again and forget the incident.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Thinking about Aruna, I am in two minds --one part of me wants her suffering to
stop and it was really hard to not cry for her, for &amp;quot;what may have been&amp;quot; when I
saw her hospital video being aired on every news channel, or while writing this
entry, or while reading for the first time all those years ago -- Aruna's
tragedy still evokes the same emotional reaction today as when I first heard
heard her story all those years ago -- A pretty nurse, brutally raped by her
subordinate, Sohanlal Bharatha Valmiki, as an &lt;a href=&quot;http://varshavnaik.wordpress.com/2006/07/05/aruna/&quot;&gt;act of revenge&lt;/a&gt; ; who
has since 1980 been a free man -- free to marry and have a family of his own ;
whose first act upon being released from jail in 1980 was to visit Aruna's room
at KEM hospital and remove the bed guards, leading to her falling from the
hospital bed. He probably thought Aruna would fall and die. She didnt.
Presumably security was raised after this second incident and her co-nurses and
doctors are her only visitors. Later the rapist moved out of the city and was
last heard working in a NewDelhi hospital under an assumed name.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;q&gt;I met a big learned pujari who said I had a sau mein ek patrika [a rare
horoscope], that I’d be a success, will live long and would go abroad..... but
even if he was talking rubbish it does not matter because I know that I will
become known in my field&lt;/q&gt; -- That was the ambitious and dynamic 25-year-old
Aruna, talking to her cousin about her career plans to pursue her dreams of
studying abroad. Eerily, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.deccanherald.com/content/143739/soothsayer-scarily-right.html&quot;&gt;soothsayer's
predictions to her father did come true&lt;/a&gt; but I doubt if this was the kind of
fame they would have wished for, nor expected.  Aruna, born on 1948June01,
was the youngest daughter of the Shanbhag family -- consisting of her parents
and siblings, six brothers and two sisters, all of who were more interested in
extracting an apartment in Mumbai and financial compensation out of her
tragedy. When that didnt materialize, they abandoned her to her fate.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For a woman who went against her family and rejected the life of abject poverty
in the village, she did well as a nurse in Mumbai, met and fell in love with
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.expressindia.com/ie/daily/19980530/15050804.html&quot;&gt;Dr.Sundeep
Sardesai&lt;/a&gt;, who upon realising that Aruna would never be normal again,
deserted her to marry another woman on 1974May01 and settled down abroad. If
you knew and loved someone so deeply would you not feel any guilt for deserting
them? I cannot help but wonder if Dr.Sardesai, even once, over these 37 years,
ever wondered how Aruna is doing. His rejection makes me wonder if he had ever
cared or loved her at all!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Apparently everyone in Aruna's life has moved on and is living a normal human
life. There is no doubt that Aruna's hellish experience has made her suffer for
37 long years but mercy-killing? Killing someone who cannot make that decision
for themselves isnt mercy. However which way I argue, it seems terribly unfair
that others get to decide when Aruna should die. How do we have the right to
make decisions on behalf of a person who, unfortunately, cannot decide for
herself!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Strange as it may sound, she seems like a fighter to me -- Didnt she overcome
her comatose state after the rape, albeit declared &amp;quot;brain-dead&amp;quot;/'persistent
vegetative state' thence. Her tremendous will to survive reflects in the fact
that despite being brain-dead she has definitely shown a will to live, and most
importantly, she can breathe on her own and isnt dependent on life-aids. The
nurses at Mumbai's King Edward Memorial (KEM) Hospital claim, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ndtv.com/article/india/aruna-shanbaug-s-caretakers-won-t-let-her-go-89675&quot;&gt;
Aruna responds to them when they attend to her&lt;/a&gt;, albeit as 'screams' or
'smiles' and they &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thehindu.com/news/article1517233.ece&quot;&gt;cheered at the Supreme
Court's verdict that Aruna should live&lt;/a&gt;. For once, I am glad that the
tax-payers money is being put to good use by a handful of KEM nurses and
doctors.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
All the people in favor of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blogher.com/rape-has-left-people-wishing-her-dead&quot;&gt;killing
(err..mercy-killing) Aruna&lt;/a&gt;, should take a moment to wonder at her
indomitable spirit her body still holds on to -- &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theaustralian.com.au/news/world/india-bars-mercy-killing-but-leaves-loophole/story-e6frg6so-1226017314370&quot;&gt;
She responds to stimuli, is on a liquid diet and loves listening to music&lt;/a&gt;
and the staff &lt;a href=&quot;http://ibnlive.in.com/news/aruna-is-the-bond-that-unites-us-kem-hospital/145221-3.html&quot;&gt;
nurses and doctors of KEM&lt;/a&gt; care more for Aruna than her family or ex-fiance
ever did. She continues to live among strangers who care enough to care for her
life. Why should we deny her the right to live?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On 2011June01, Aruna Shanbhag will not know she turned 63, as she has
remained oblivious to all her birthdays since 1973November27, but that is not
reason enough to permit euthanasia. Let us not kill someone who, despite two
murder attempts on her life, has shown such tremendous will to live. She has
survived despite the odds stacked against her and she should be allowed to die
when her body chooses it, naturally. That, for me, is mercy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If reading about Aruna was heart-wrenching, writing this blog entry was
equally difficult, especially because I wanted an appropriate title in Marathi,
one that could reflect Aruna Shanbhag's strong never-say-die spirit, choosing
to outlive her tragedy by 37 long years (and probably many more to come), only
to remind Indians (and the world?) that as a society, and as a nation, we
conveniently choose to forget the silent, the inconvenient, the speechless and
actively deny justice to women who are rape victims. Its ironic to be forgotten
by the next generation you supposedly bring forth!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Sanskrit, &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sanskrit-lexicon.uni-koeln.de/cgi-bin/tamil/recherche&quot;&gt;Mukta&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;has
various meanings: &amp;quot;finally set free&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;liberated, delivered, emancipated (esp.
from sin or worldly existence)&amp;quot; ; as also meaning &amp;quot;abandoned, relinquished,
given up , laid aside&amp;quot; ; &amp;quot;the quarter or cardinal point just quitted by the
sun&amp;quot; [ironically, her first name 'Aruna'; means &amp;quot;the red colour of the morning
sun&amp;quot;] ; unchaste woman; &amp;quot;the spirit released from corporeal existence&amp;quot; (a noun
form). How ironic!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, Aruna is already mukta -- she, whose ruddy spirit wills her to live,
despite the cruel betrayals by those she loved, the society and the Indian
legal system! I cant even begin to imagine the pain Aruna may have gone through
but instead of killing her in the name of mercy, we should be fighting to
update the ancient rape laws in India -- bring them on par to those followed in
developed nations like USA, Europe, et al. Lets petition to change Indian laws
and make it impossible for an Aruna Ramchandra Shanbhag redux, ever! That, for
me, would be true mercy towards all Indian women and each day would be Indian
Women's Day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dnaindia.com/mumbai/report_aruna-shanbaugs-care-givers-at-kem-hospital-celebrate-apex-courts-lease-of-life_1517053&quot;&gt;
Tasting crystals of sugar fed by sister Sugandha Rokade in her mouth, nurse
Aruna Shanbaug, 62, cried out, “Aaah!” when she was told about the Supreme
Court judgment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-03-07T12:39:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:md5:d4a7df9f8f23e154aeb4110c4d81277b">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: beware of spammers asking for your account password</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2011/beware-of-spammers-asking-for-your-account-password</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;If you've got a mail with the subject line &amp;quot;&lt;span id=&quot;:1m5&quot; class=&quot;hP&quot;&gt;Account System Update&amp;quot;, asking for your &amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;Passvvord&amp;quot; &lt;span id=&quot;:1m5&quot; class=&quot;hP&quot;&gt;(gee, atleast spell it right :/), because they are shutting down
your account, .... Simply delete it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;:1m5&quot; class=&quot;hP&quot;&gt;Notice the headers, its not from Google or&lt;/span&gt;
Gmail and you would be safer not responding to them. I'm not sure if google has
a feedback system where I can submit this so I thought its better to blog and
tell the whole world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delivered-To: s***@gmail.com&lt;br /&gt;
Received: by 10.236.95.41 with SMTP id o29cs221272yhf;&lt;br /&gt;
Mon, 21 Feb 2011 16:29:35 -0800 (PST)&lt;br /&gt;
Received: by 10.224.28.66 with SMTP id l2mr1663334qac.68.1298334565437;&lt;br /&gt;
Mon, 21 Feb 2011 16:29:25 -0800 (PST)&lt;br /&gt;
Return-Path: &amp;lt;nobody@alexander.ourhostingservers.com&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Received: from alexander.ourhostingservers.com (alexander.ourhostingservers.com
[75.126.65.69])&lt;br /&gt;
by mx.google.com with ESMTPS id m15si11781389qck.51.2011.02.21.16.29.25&lt;br /&gt;
(version=TLSv1/SSLv3 cipher=OTHER);&lt;br /&gt;
Mon, 21 Feb 2011 16:29:25 -0800 (PST)&lt;br /&gt;
Received-SPF: pass (google.com: best guess record for domain of
nobody@alexander.ourhostingservers.com designates 75.126.65.69 as permitted
sender) client-ip=75.126.65.69;&lt;br /&gt;
Authentication-Results: mx.google.com; spf=pass (google.com: best guess record
for domain of nobody@alexander.ourhostingservers.com designates 75.126.65.69 as
permitted sender) smtp.mail=nobody@alexander.ourhostingservers.com&lt;br /&gt;
Received: from nobody by alexander.ourhostingservers.com with local (Exim
4.69)&lt;br /&gt;
(envelope-from &amp;lt;nobody@alexander.ourhostingservers.com&amp;gt;)&lt;br /&gt;
id 1PrfGY-0000BR-P5&lt;br /&gt;
for s***@gmail.com; Mon, 21 Feb 2011 17:34:06 -0600&lt;br /&gt;
To: s***@gmail.com&lt;br /&gt;
Subject: Account System Update&lt;br /&gt;
X-PHP-Script: ex-dn.com/e107_themes/inbox.php for 41.31.241.220&lt;br /&gt;
From: Gmail &amp;lt;verifyscevsces@gmail.com&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Reply-To: verifyscevsces@gmail.com&lt;br /&gt;
MIME-Version: 1.0&lt;br /&gt;
Content-Type: text/plain&lt;br /&gt;
Content-Transfer-Encoding: 8bit&lt;br /&gt;
Message-Id: &amp;lt;E1PrfGY-0000BR-P5@alexander.ourhostingservers.com&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Date: Mon, 21 Feb 2011 17:34:06 -0600&lt;br /&gt;
X-AntiAbuse: This header was added to track abuse, please include it with any
abuse report&lt;br /&gt;
X-AntiAbuse: Primary Hostname - alexander.ourhostingservers.com&lt;br /&gt;
X-AntiAbuse: Original Domain - gmail.com&lt;br /&gt;
X-AntiAbuse: Originator/Caller UID/GID - [99 32002] / [47 12]&lt;br /&gt;
X-AntiAbuse: Sender Address Domain - alexander.ourhostingservers.com&lt;br /&gt;
X-Source:&lt;br /&gt;
X-Source-Args:&lt;br /&gt;
X-Source-Dir:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We are shutting down some accounts due to congestion in our database system and
your account was chosen to be deleted automatically. To avoid permanent lockup,
kindly click reply and fill in the space below for verification purpose:-&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Account ID&lt;br /&gt;
Passvvord&lt;br /&gt;
Registered Year (MM/YYYY)&lt;br /&gt;
Designation Field:&lt;br /&gt;
Direct Phone:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Note: This email is only for Gmail users (Users should reply within 48 hours to
avoid &amp;quot;Permanently Lockup&amp;quot; Account)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Thank you for using Gmail !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-02-22T06:30:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://barkha.in/blog/?p=145">
	<title>Certified crazy: These days</title>
	<link>http://barkha.in/blog/2011/02/18/these-days/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;These days a lot of idiots manage to piss me off &amp;#8211; either that, or my patience levels have gone really low. These days I feel more like punching some people right in the face, hard enough to break their nose. To vent my frustration away, for days like these, I keep handy a bag full of empty bottles of wine. Getting rid of them at the garbage triage for glass bottles gives immense satisfaction. With every&lt;em&gt; clink &lt;/em&gt;that the bottle goes down in the wooden container, my brain feels a little lighter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thats my plan for the weekend to get rid of the frustration. Whats yours?&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-02-18T10:20:30+00:00</dc:date>
	<dc:creator>barkha</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:md5:6eb9b80ff562205eeb7377fba2a483d9">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: GSoC-2011 invites small FLOSS projects</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2011/GSoC-2011-invites-small-FLOSS-projects</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;On the heels of &lt;a href=&quot;http://svaksha.com/post/2010/google-code-in-2010&quot;&gt;GCI&lt;/a&gt; ending a
few days ago, &lt;a href=&quot;http://google-opensource.blogspot.com/2011/01/google-summer-of-code-announced-at-lca.html&quot;&gt;
GSOC-2011 was announced at LCA&lt;/a&gt;. This year there is an important change,
that of the participating organizations, as per Carol's mail (below),
http://lists.p2pu.org/pipermail/p2pu-dev/2011-February/000288.html :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;--&lt;br /&gt;
On Tue, 8 Feb 2011, Carol Smith wrote:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Hi all,&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Per some feedback from the mentor summit last year, I've decided to&lt;br /&gt;
encourage and accept more small and new mentoring organizations this
year.&lt;br /&gt;
In tandem with more organizations, I am also setting up a separate
mailing&lt;br /&gt;
list for the newbie organizations to subscribe to to get advice on how to&lt;br /&gt;
successfully participate in the program for the summer.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I need your help with this effort. If you know of small/new projects who
are&lt;br /&gt;
doing interesting work in the opensource space who might not otherwise&lt;br /&gt;
apply, please encourage them to do so. We're looking for all kinds of new&lt;br /&gt;
orgs - ones doing stuff on the bleeding edge, ones opensourcing stuff
that&lt;br /&gt;
hasn't been before, ones who might get overlooked because they're
otherwise&lt;br /&gt;
too small.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There will be two special questions on the mentoring organization&lt;br /&gt;
application this year: one for which a large or experienced organization
can&lt;br /&gt;
vouch for a small, new organization and one for new or small
organizations&lt;br /&gt;
to list their &amp;quot;references&amp;quot; in the form of veteran orgs or people. These
two&lt;br /&gt;
questions will be looked at very specifically when we review organization&lt;br /&gt;
applications this year so please fill them in if they are applicable for&lt;br /&gt;
you.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
To facilitate the mentor/mentee relationship between orgs I've set up a&lt;br /&gt;
mailing list for both veteran and newbie mentors to join [1]. Please sign
up&lt;br /&gt;
if you feel comfortable offering advice to new organizations on how to&lt;br /&gt;
participate in a successful GSoC. I've made this list invite-only, so
please&lt;br /&gt;
request membership if you're interested in joining and list the org you&lt;br /&gt;
mentor for. After we've announced accepted organizations for this year,
the&lt;br /&gt;
mentors and org admins from the new projects will be automatically&lt;br /&gt;
subscribed to this list and encouraged to ask questions and get advice.&lt;br /&gt;
**This will be a chatty list.**&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Thank you in advance for your help with this effort, and may this be the&lt;br /&gt;
most awesome summer yet!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[1] - &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/gsoc-veterans&quot;&gt;http://groups.google.com/group/gsoc-veterans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;
Cheers,&lt;br /&gt;
Carol&lt;br /&gt;
--&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, Google is inviting all fledgling free software projects to
apply and there is a concerted effort to rope in smaller organizations doing
nice things in Libre software this year. So if you know any organization or
floss project that should be a part of gsoc, encourage them to join the mailing
list and apply for 2011. [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE,2011feb25&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Here is a
&lt;a href=&quot;https://spreadsheets.google.com/ccc?key=0AgfaVN-Bzcp0dDNkS1ZETEU0UzVlYmNVTFdpaW4zZXc&amp;amp;hl=en#gid=0&quot;&gt;
spreadsheet of the FLOSS organizations applying for GSOC-2011&lt;/a&gt;, but do
remember that this is NOT a final list which is entirely upto Google.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like FLOSS projects, GSOC is perhaps the only technical event that is open
to students in any stream (you could be studying for your B.A in literature and
still participate in GSOC), does not have artificial barriers which perpetuate
a myth that only Engineers or Computer Science students can use, decode and
contribute to FLOSS. Any student can, provided they put in some effort to
understanding the Libre software ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So go ahead, download and use their &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/google-summer-of-code/wiki/ProgramPresentations&quot;&gt;presentations&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/google-summer-of-code/wiki/GsocLogos&quot;&gt;logos&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/google-summer-of-code/wiki/GsocFlyers&quot;&gt;flyers&lt;/a&gt; to
promote Gsoc in your college or university, spread the word and participate
when the list of accepted projects is announced in March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE,2011feb28&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Google has opened the
application process for mentoring organizations for Google Summer of Code 2011
which are being accepted at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google-melange.com&quot;&gt;Melange&lt;/a&gt;
for ALL Libre software organizations. Please note that the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google-melange.com/document/show/gsoc_program/google/gsoc2011/timeline&quot;&gt;
application period&lt;/a&gt; closes on &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/paMZU&quot;&gt;11 March at
23:00 UTC&lt;/a&gt;.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-02-08T23:58:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:lj:livejournal.com:atom1:kadambarid:81865">
	<title>kadambarid: Rediscovering the creative side</title>
	<link>http://kadambarid.livejournal.com/81865.html</link>
	<content:encoded>I'm on a break from research, of a particular kind. From abstract, logical math and computer science. From writing papers and listening to lectures on algorithms to solve every problem in the world. From picking out pure math talks by (formerly) Israeli academics, and evangelizing Linux and anything FOSS-y. From programming, technical writing, and copy-editing gargantuan (and boring) books on programming for major publishing houses. From attending geek conferences, hackathons, and tutorials (as both presenter and learner). From being an RA to an utter [insert profanity] of a professor. From slogging over assignments on complexity theory and fretting over tests involving shortest paths and spanning trees. From churning out papers and sending them to conferences. From being fascinated by game theory but wanting to jump to applied CS. From the sneers of CS theorists, who think that anyone else doing anything else has the brain of a teenager from the dark ages. From tearing my hair over all kinds of things, and having an upset stomach before every exam, conference talk, and presentation!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I'm instead exploring my creative side. Not intentionally, but serendipitously. Spontaneously and intuitively - how apt, me thinks! It started with music. With some time on my hands (finally!), having abandoned grad school (possibly temporarily) to get a life, work on my marriage (long distance simply did not work; I was stupid to think it would!) and take stock of my transitioning interest in a field far flung from my studies and research till then, and having long wanted to learn to play the guitar, I grabbed the first opportunity that presented itself. I'm still learning, but find the learning process to be unlike any other musical training I've received. I'll reserve the &quot;Why?&quot; for another post; just suffice to say that the teacher is excellent, and even just randomly strumming on the guitar sounds good (unlike say a violin or the flute - a beginner trying random sounds in these offers a cacophonous hell!). Additionally, my partner's exploits, focus, and methods, are fun and inspiring.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Alongside music started other pursuits that I had always wanted to spend time doing but always took the back-burner - birdwatching and photography. Where I live had an important role to play where this was concerned. IIT Bombay is a haven for birdwatching, and I managed to get good guidance and plenty of opportunity to pursue this more actively. Encouragement and support, including setting-up &quot;equipment&quot;, was provided by my partner and parents. Wildlife photography entails a lot of expensive gadgets - DSLRs, lenses of good quality and range, and other paraphernalia cost a small fortune. Talk about expensive interests/obsessions! And, now my birdwatching is no longer restricted to the campus; we're going farther and farther every month ... :)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The break has also provided me with plenty of opportunity to travel, explore, take part in adventure sports, play indoor and outdoor games, write, cook &amp;amp; bake, catch up on my reading list, and what not. The latest in a series of things I've always wanted to do or have not done in a long while, or have never had the time to indulge in is : Art.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When in Madras on a small holiday and to attend a friend's engagement, I found an empty board of canvas that my budding artist of a cousin in his teens had to spare. A casual enquiry led to him agreeing to &quot;tutor&quot; me; we have come a full circle - I remember teaching him to color and paint when he was a toddler :) IMO, he is something of a prodigy where art is concerned - never joining contests, but turning to art whenever he feels like doing &quot;something&quot;, ever since a kid, and barely a teen now.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here's the progression:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Day 1:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000fzx28/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000fzx28/s640x480&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000g07sk/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000g07sk/s640x480&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Day 2:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000g1z26/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000g1z26/s640x480&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000g2a83/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000g2a83/s640x480&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Day 3:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000g3yw5/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000g3yw5/s640x480&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000g4thf/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000g4thf/s640x480&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For an oil painting, I didn't spend too much time on it and it was a relatively uncomplicated piece to work on. I liked working on something in a focused manner without jumping tabs and windows, and managing to finish an oil painting in under a week. While bringing it to Mumbai, I had to carry it in a plastic case since it wasn't dry as yet, and was asked by many people if it was a real &quot;kachua&quot; :) The painting created a flutter in the Chennai airport security area, with all the guards passing it around for inspection, amidst much oohing and aahing. Random people's appreciation is rather encouraging, especially since I'm a beginner.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Very importantly, I'm busy as ever - but in a nice way. An idle mind is indeed the devil's workshop. I'm comfortable doing these things, and happy. I'm not always burnt out, high strung, or stressed out, like I used to be. I'd be ready to delve into what I've decided to pursue in a little while - almost there already.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I'm happy.</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2011-02-08T16:59:37+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://archu.wordpress.com/2010/12/21/cool-cooler-coldest-not-liking-this/">
	<title>Archu's Cyberspace...!: archu</title>
	<link>http://archu.wordpress.com/2010/12/21/cool-cooler-coldest-not-liking-this/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;cool, cooler, coldest.. not liking this cold weather.. esp thinking its chennai&amp;#8230; &lt;img src=&quot;http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif&quot; alt=&quot;:(&quot; class=&quot;wp-smiley&quot; /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/archu.wordpress.com/755/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/archu.wordpress.com/755/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=archu.wordpress.com&amp;#038;blog=373911&amp;#038;post=755&amp;#038;subd=archu&amp;#038;ref=&amp;#038;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2010-12-21T14:42:32+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:md5:e0c305c23f3e311c153e75023786dc32">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: Smartmontools load_cycle_count</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2010/Smartmontools-load_cycle_count</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Dear Lazyweb,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have installed &amp;quot;smartmontools&amp;quot; on your laptop on Ubuntu-Lucid, has it
been behaving erratically after the last update about a week ago?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;me@ubuntu:~$ sudo smartctl -s on -a /dev/sda &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;smartctl version 5.38 [i686-pc-linux-gnu] Copyright (C) 2002-8 Bruce
Allen&lt;br /&gt;
Home page is http://smartmontools.sourceforge.net/&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
=== START OF INFORMATION SECTION ===&lt;br /&gt;
Model Family:     Seagate Momentus 5400.3&lt;br /&gt;
Device Model:     ST9160821AS&lt;br /&gt;
Serial Number:    5MA1LL40&lt;br /&gt;
Firmware Version: 3.BHD&lt;br /&gt;
User Capacity:    160,041,885,696 bytes&lt;br /&gt;
Device is:        In smartctl database [for
details use: -P show]&lt;br /&gt;
ATA Version is:   7&lt;br /&gt;
ATA Standard is:  Exact ATA specification draft version not
indicated&lt;br /&gt;
Local Time is:    Fri Dec 17 11:09:46 2010 UTC&lt;br /&gt;
SMART support is: Available - device has SMART capability.&lt;br /&gt;
SMART support is: Enabled&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
=== START OF ENABLE/DISABLE COMMANDS SECTION ===&lt;br /&gt;
SMART Enabled.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
=== START OF READ SMART DATA SECTION ===&lt;br /&gt;
SMART overall-health self-assessment test result: PASSED&lt;br /&gt;
See vendor-specific Attribute list for marginal Attributes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
General SMART Values:&lt;br /&gt;
Offline data collection status:  (0x82)    Offline data
collection activity&lt;br /&gt;
               
    was completed without error.&lt;br /&gt;
               
    Auto Offline Data Collection: Enabled.&lt;br /&gt;
Self-test execution status:      ( 
21)    The self-test routine was aborted by&lt;br /&gt;
               
    the host.&lt;br /&gt;
Total time to complete Offline&lt;br /&gt;
data collection:          ( 426)
seconds.&lt;br /&gt;
Offline data collection&lt;br /&gt;
capabilities:            
 (0x53) SMART execute Offline immediate.&lt;br /&gt;
               
    Auto Offline data collection on/off support.&lt;br /&gt;
               
    Suspend Offline collection upon new&lt;br /&gt;
               
    command.&lt;br /&gt;
               
    No Offline surface scan supported.&lt;br /&gt;
               
    Self-test supported.&lt;br /&gt;
               
    No Conveyance Self-test supported.&lt;br /&gt;
               
    Selective Self-test supported.&lt;br /&gt;
SMART
capabilities:           
(0x0003)    Saves SMART data before entering&lt;br /&gt;
               
    power-saving mode.&lt;br /&gt;
               
    Supports SMART auto save timer.&lt;br /&gt;
Error logging capability:       
(0x01)    Error logging supported.&lt;br /&gt;
               
    No General Purpose Logging support.&lt;br /&gt;
Short self-test routine&lt;br /&gt;
recommended polling time:      (   2)
minutes.&lt;br /&gt;
Extended self-test routine&lt;br /&gt;
recommended polling time:      (  88) minutes.&lt;br /&gt;
SCT capabilities:           
(0x0001)    SCT Status supported.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
SMART Attributes Data Structure revision number: 10&lt;br /&gt;
Vendor Specific SMART Attributes with Thresholds:&lt;br /&gt;
ID# ATTRIBUTE_NAME         
FLAG     VALUE WORST THRESH
TYPE      UPDATED  WHEN_FAILED RAW_VALUE&lt;br /&gt;
  1 Raw_Read_Error_Rate     0x000f  
105   096   006    Pre-fail 
Always      
-       9940165&lt;br /&gt;
  3
Spin_Up_Time           
0x0002   099   098   000   
Old_age   Always      
-       0&lt;br /&gt;
  4 Start_Stop_Count       
0x0033   098   098   020   
Pre-fail  Always      
-       2683&lt;br /&gt;
  5 Reallocated_Sector_Ct   0x0033   100  
100   036    Pre-fail 
Always      
-       0&lt;br /&gt;
  7 Seek_Error_Rate        
0x000f   072   060   030   
Pre-fail  Always      
-       17255855270&lt;br /&gt;
  9 Power_On_Hours         
0x0032   096   096   000   
Old_age   Always      
-       3998&lt;br /&gt;
 10 Spin_Retry_Count       
0x0013   100   100   034   
Pre-fail  Always      
-       0&lt;br /&gt;
 12 Power_Cycle_Count      
0x0033   098   098   020   
Pre-fail  Always      
-       2155&lt;br /&gt;
187 Reported_Uncorrect      0x0032  
100   100   000    Old_age  
Always      
-       0&lt;br /&gt;
189 High_Fly_Writes        
0x003a   100   100   000   
Old_age   Always      
-       0&lt;br /&gt;
190 Airflow_Temperature_Cel 0x0022   049   035  
045    Old_age   Always   In_the_past 51 (15
36 54 47)&lt;br /&gt;
192 Power-Off_Retract_Count 0x0032   100   100  
000    Old_age  
Always      
-       1159&lt;br /&gt;
193 Load_Cycle_Count       
0x0032   001   001   000   
Old_age   Always      
-       227684&lt;br /&gt;
194 Temperature_Celsius     0x0022  
051   065   000    Old_age  
Always      
-       51 (0 18 0 0)&lt;br /&gt;
195 Hardware_ECC_Recovered  0x001a   078  
060   000    Old_age  
Always      
-       64509422&lt;br /&gt;
197 Current_Pending_Sector  0x0012   100  
100   000    Old_age  
Always      
-       1&lt;br /&gt;
198 Offline_Uncorrectable   0x0010   100  
100   000    Old_age  
Offline      -      
1&lt;br /&gt;
199 UDMA_CRC_Error_Count    0x003e   200  
200   000    Old_age  
Always      
-       0&lt;br /&gt;
200 Multi_Zone_Error_Rate   0x0000   100  
253   000    Old_age  
Offline      -      
0&lt;br /&gt;
202 TA_Increase_Count       0x0032  
100   253   000    Old_age  
Always      
-       0&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
SMART Error Log Version: 1&lt;br /&gt;
No Errors Logged&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
SMART Self-test log structure revision number 1&lt;br /&gt;
Num  Test_Description   
Status                 
Remaining  LifeTime(hours)  LBA_of_first_error&lt;br /&gt;
# 1  Extended offline    Aborted by
host              
50%     
2943         -&lt;br /&gt;
# 2  Extended offline    Aborted by
host              
70%     
2699         -&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
SMART Selective self-test log data structure revision number 1&lt;br /&gt;
 SPAN  MIN_LBA  MAX_LBA  CURRENT_TEST_STATUS&lt;br /&gt;
    1       
0        0  Not_testing&lt;br /&gt;
    2       
0        0  Not_testing&lt;br /&gt;
    3       
0        0  Not_testing&lt;br /&gt;
    4       
0        0  Not_testing&lt;br /&gt;
    5       
0        0  Not_testing&lt;br /&gt;
Selective self-test flags (0x0):&lt;br /&gt;
  After scanning selected spans, do NOT read-scan remainder of disk.&lt;br /&gt;
If Selective self-test is pending on power-up, resume after 0 minute
delay.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;As you can see here, &lt;a href=&quot;http://paste.ubuntu.com/544820/&quot;&gt;there is no LCC&lt;/a&gt; for desktop server
hard-disks and its especially meant for laptop HDD, where I'm interested in
limiting the Load_Cycle_Count (LCC) to increment &lt;strong&gt;only&lt;/strong&gt; with
each boot cycle. Yeah, it has &lt;a href=&quot;http://svaksha.com/post/2008/hdd-health&quot;&gt;inherent
risks&lt;/a&gt;, but...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;strong&gt;193 Load_Cycle_Count       
0x0032   001   001   000   
Old_age   Always      
-       227825&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, since (the lucid update) last week, running 'smartctl' has not worked
its magic since the count has incremented from
&lt;code&gt;&lt;strong&gt;227684&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;&lt;strong&gt;227825&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
within an hour. I've been randomly checking it every other hour or so to find
the LCC racing away.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Is this a sign that the HDD is dying? Is this a hardware issue or has the
code-base changed to require a rebuild? What am I missing here?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2010-12-17T11:51:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://barkha.in/blog/?p=142">
	<title>Certified crazy: Qotd</title>
	<link>http://barkha.in/blog/2010/12/02/qotd-10/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not upset that you lied to me, I&amp;#8217;m upset that from now on I can&amp;#8217;t believe you.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;#8211; Nietzsche&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reminds me of an incident that happened one cold night a long time ago.. but that is a story for yet another post.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2010-12-02T14:35:08+00:00</dc:date>
	<dc:creator>barkha</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4752247183054428289.post-3011788326889941224">
	<title>YAB: Yet Another Blog: Scrobbling now from Kobol :)</title>
	<link>http://thisisyab.blogspot.com/2010/11/scrobbling-now-from-kobol.html</link>
	<content:encoded>In case you know about last.fm scrobbling and wondering what the hell is Kobol, well its a last.fm app that I created over the last weekend and named it such 'coz it just has such a nice ring to it. :) In case you are not familiar with BSG, its a planet in BSG world, so its something like saying 'scrobbling now from Krypton/Moon etc' :)&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Its a rare thing for the lazy me to go create stuff like this, mainly 'coz -&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;I'm lazy&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It should excite me a lot or should be a really very serious itch to overcome 1.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;div&gt;Last time it happened was while scratching my &lt;a href=&quot;http://thisisyab.blogspot.com/2008/03/lastfm-support-for-pidgin.html&quot;&gt;last.fm support for pidgin&lt;/a&gt; itch. In this case, it wasn't exactly my itch but rather my friend's itch that began it all. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Now my friend is what you call as a 'purist' and considers me as some sort of last.fm expert(mainly 'coz I introduced it to him I think). And so a month or two back he asks me - &lt;blockquote&gt;'Playing your own library is fine but the songs get repetitive after a while, so how do I get last.fm to play more songs from the same artists and not any others'.&lt;/blockquote&gt;If you are not a last.fm subscriber, then you would know that there is very limited last.fm radios that you can listen to. You can listen to your library radio or similar artists radio etc but there is no way you can just listen to a selected artist radio i.e songs from only that artist and not from any other.  And since my purist friend didn't want to corrupt his library by listening to other radios, I suggested to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.we7.com&quot;&gt;we7  &lt;/a&gt;or spotify which have last.fm scrobbling integrated. But they turned out to be UK only services, some consolation win for us UK folks denied of Pandora! :)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Well anyway it was then that the evil idea stuck me, 'All you need to get songs in your library is to just scrobble them and to scrobble all you need is artist and track name, so effectively all you need is a program that scrobbles from such a file'. Sadly my friend didn't want to code and so I forgot all about it, as it wasn't my itch after all! &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;But then last weekend, I came across this in my GReader - &lt;a href=&quot;http://google-opensource.blogspot.com/2010/11/announcing-google-refine-20-power-tool.html&quot;&gt;http://google-opensource.blogspot.com/2010/11/announcing-google-refine-20-power-tool.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Which made me revisit that idea. One of the unpleasant tasks involved in the above idea is in creating the actual tracks file, where to get the data, who will copy paste etc. But then I saw Google Refine videos and I was like 'wow'! And I thought with the freebase integration it just takes matter of few clicks to create the artist-tracks file you want! Since I wanted to try out Google Refine, thought why not go ahead and implement that program after all, that way I too can get new artists that I wanted to listen to into my library ;) And while I was at it thought why not learn some basic python as well and thats how it started!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Soon after I started, I hit limitations in freebase, for one thing the artist names in Freebase weren't a perfect match with ones in last.fm. Also I couldn't figure out a way to get albums by an artist and tracks in that album, which was what had excited me in first place. Maybe I just needed to dig into the refine documentation a bit more but I was already bored.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;So I just created a script that fetches the top tracks of a given artist from last.fm and writes to a csv. And you feed this csv to the other script which scrobbles the tracks in the csv. Now if anyone can find a good way to fetch the albums of an artist as well and the tracks in that album that will be brilliant!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;If you are interested in scrobbling from a file, to listen to new artists or just to increase your scrobble count, then you can get the scripts here &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/site/recapitulations/getTracks.py&quot;&gt;getTracks.py&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/site/recapitulations/lastfm.py&quot;&gt;lastfm.py&lt;/a&gt; . Only thing you need to do is obtain your own unique API_KEY and API_SECRET values from http://www.last.fm/api/account and replace the sample values in the script.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Since its from Kobol, this post has to end with &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;'so say we all' &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/4752247183054428289-3011788326889941224?l=thisisyab.blogspot.com&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2010-11-21T01:29:35+00:00</dc:date>
	<dc:creator>Puthali</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://netra.wordpress.com/?p=374">
	<title>Netra's Weblog: Netra</title>
	<link>http://netra.wordpress.com/2010/11/12/girly-vacation-in-goa/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;My best friend and me were on our regular Saturday phone call. 15 minutes into the call and we both were certain we had to do something to keep the boredom in life at bay. Then came this plan of executing our long planned holiday plan. Goa was our choice. &amp;#8220;Wow, sun kissed beaches, old temples, beautiful churches.. It ll be an awesome girly vacation&amp;#8221;, we fantasized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when we informed(asked for consent to be appropriate) our parents about it, the first reaction was &amp;#8220;Goa? only two of you girls?? Have you gone mad???&amp;#8221;. Then came 100s of examples derived from newspaper articles, magazine cover stories, rumors from reliable sources to prove why our plan of going to Goa was terrible. But people, WE ARE SMART GIRLS B-) . We managed to convince them with &amp;#8220;We are really bored in life, we need this vacation to be alive and happy&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;Sneha&amp;#8217;s classmate lives there, Amma! And we have that aunt&amp;#8217;s first daughter living in there.. remember? We&amp;#8217;ll be fine&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;Please please please, wont you give me 3 days out of my own life?!&amp;#8221;.. effect of watching too many bollywood movies, may be. In our hearts, we knew its kind of risky for us to manage in Goa alone. However, we really needed a break from routine to relax and feel good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sneha came home and picked me up on that Sunday. We were to head to her place, Belgaum, first. That evening we shopped though we needed &amp;#8220;absolutely nothing new&amp;#8221; for that vacation. &amp;#8220;Come on, We are going on a vacation! How pretty would those pink shoes look? And that cool black and white stole, made for Goa&amp;#8221; -  we thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day, after 3.5 hrs and innumerable irritations about the winding roads, we arrived in Goa. The flavor of the day was Calangute beach; beautiful, safe. Considering non-alcoholic, pure vegetarian, non party-freak style of ours, the Goa streets seemed slightly odd to us. With God&amp;#8217;s grace, we found a BR store near our resort.. now thats what i call indulgence!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a slideshow of some of our pics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://netra.wordpress.com/2010/11/12/girly-vacation-in-goa/#gallery-374-1-slideshow&quot;&gt;Click to view slideshow.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the second day, we went for sight seeing in South Goa. Colossal churches, stunning temples and bewitching beaches marked our day. We adored Dona Paula for its scenic beauty and Colva beach for its fine sand. I am mesmerized by the infinity the sea represents.. makes me feel boundless, makes me feel that i stand for all the wonderful things in the universe!  &lt;img src=&quot;http://s1.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif&quot; alt=&quot;;)&quot; class=&quot;wp-smiley&quot; /&gt;  We also enjoyed at the evening cruse on Mandovi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third day morning was the most memorable. We went to Calangute beach early in the morning and played on the sea shore to our heart&amp;#8217;s content. Later in the day, we bought gifts for mom, dad, sis, bro and friends. Rains slashed our plans of visiting more beaches, though we enjoyed the rains. We bid Good Bye to Goa and left for Belgaum in the evening, gathering memories of friendship for a lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, it was an awesome Girly Vacation as planned &lt;img src=&quot;http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; class=&quot;wp-smiley&quot; /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/netra.wordpress.com/374/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/netra.wordpress.com/374/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/netra.wordpress.com/374/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/netra.wordpress.com/374/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/netra.wordpress.com/374/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/netra.wordpress.com/374/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/netra.wordpress.com/374/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/netra.wordpress.com/374/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/netra.wordpress.com/374/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/netra.wordpress.com/374/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/netra.wordpress.com/374/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/netra.wordpress.com/374/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/netra.wordpress.com/374/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/netra.wordpress.com/374/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=netra.wordpress.com&amp;#038;blog=2323676&amp;#038;post=374&amp;#038;subd=netra&amp;#038;ref=&amp;#038;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2010-11-12T13:13:54+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://opensourcebuzz.technetra.com/?p=429">
	<title>Open Source Buzz: What’s interesting: Learning from Twitter. Dries on Drupal. RHEL 6 finally arrives.</title>
	<link>http://opensourcebuzz.technetra.com/2010/11/11/whats-interesting-twitter-drupal-rhel/</link>
	<content:encoded>Good reading on the pitfalls faced while startups and open source grow at dizzying rates. And a major new version of Red Hat Linux emerges.
Twitter&amp;#8217;s learning experiences about fast growth, new found success and founders working (or rather not working) together. A fascinating account of how co-founders often aren&amp;#8217;t good managers, team builders or executives [...]</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2010-11-12T00:15:52+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:md5:e7c63da8aaf7aac526d74f2fb069f230">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: Google Code-In 2010</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2010/Google-Code-In-2010</link>
	<content:encoded>Today Google announced the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google-melange.com/gci/program/accepted_orgs/google/gci2010&quot;&gt;list
of participating organizations&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/gci&quot;&gt;Google Code-in&lt;/a&gt; --earlier known as GHOP, is
targeting school-going teens (upper age limit is 18 years) to contribute to
Free/Libre software projects. The Code-in starts on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google-melange.com/document/show/gci_program/google/gci2010/timeline&quot;&gt;
2010-Nov-22&lt;/a&gt;, so do read up on all the &lt;a href=&quot;http://google-opensource.blogspot.com/2010/11/announcing-accepted-organizations-for.html&quot;&gt;
organization's task lists&lt;/a&gt; and encourage your family, friends, and
colleagues to participate!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ins&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;: Carol had posted a longer mail to a private
list, which is more informative than my two-line post &lt;img src=&quot;http://svaksha.com/themes/default/smilies/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; class=&quot;smiley&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We’re pleased to announce the Google Code-in contest starting this
22-November-2010 and ending on 10-January-2011. This contest is modelled on the
success of our pilot program, the Google Highly Open Participation Contest,
that was run in 2007-08. We will again be giving 13-18 year old students around
the world an opportunity to get involved with open source projects by doing
tasks ranging from documentation to outreach to hands-on coding. We're hoping
to get lots of women involved in this effort, so we're hoping you'll spread the
word about it, or participate yourself if you are eligible.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The participating open source projects that will be serving as mentoring
organizations have been chosen from past participants in Google Summer of Code
for their commitment to working with younger students as well as their overall
mentoring skills. The 20 organizations - twice as many as were in our pilot
program - are listed on our site at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google-melange.com/gci/program/accepted_orgs/google/gci2010&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.google-melange.com/gci/program/accepted_orgs/google/gci2010&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;
The participants have a chance to earn prizes including cash and teeshirts,
with 10 grand prize winners receiving a trip to Google headquarters in Mountain
View, California for an awards ceremony. Grand Prize contest winners will be
announced on 14, February, 2011.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We’re looking forward to a fun contest this year and hope you’ll consider
participating yourself if you are eligible or spread the word to friends,
family, and colleagues about the program.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We encourage you to join the Google Code-in contest discussion list: &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/gci-discuss&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://groups.google.com/group/gci-discuss&lt;/a&gt; and announcement
list:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/gci-announce&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://groups.google.com/group/gci-announce&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Please see our blog post: &lt;a href=&quot;http://google-opensource.blogspot.com/2010/10/google-code-in-schools-out-codes-in.htmlfor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://google-opensource.blogspot.com/2010/10/google-code-in-schools-out-codes-in.html&lt;/a&gt;
for further details and feel free to contact me directly if you have specific
questions that aren’t answered on the website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/gci&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://code.google.com/gci&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Cheers,&lt;br /&gt;
Carol Smith&lt;br /&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2010-11-05T17:53:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:md5:a0c2433f0e14eeab8432f21970683c62">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: Extract .msi archive format on Ubuntu</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2010/Extract-.msi-archive-format-on-Ubuntu</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I was googling for some information which was only available in a .msi
archive format which I could not extract directly on ubuntu. Since I didnt have
windows on the machine, I could not extract it there and just copy the files
over to linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On ubuntu, installing WINE (and trying to extract with msiexec) didnt work
-- wine kept whining about it not being an executable (on linux? *g*), the
source being from an untrusted source, etc...&lt;/p&gt;
Next, I tried &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.7-zip.org/&quot;&gt;p7zip&lt;/a&gt; -- install it with
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sudo apt-get install p7zip-full&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Then, change directories, and type:
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7z x filename.msi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
While this extracts all the files, it will still not be easily viewable nor is
it usable -- windows executable dlls, bitmaps, windows installer package,
microsoft cabinet archive, some icons, and other useless cruft compressed in
the folder. Other than manually digging out text files for the information,
there was no easy option.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The data was locked inside the database (hint, extract the cabinet archive) in
the .mbd (MS Access) format. Google threw some &lt;a href=&quot;http://mdbtools.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;perl modules&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.perlmonks.org/?node_id=452217&quot;&gt;convert a .mbd file to .txt&lt;/a&gt;. BUT
there was a gnome mbd-reader tool which you can easily install with
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sudo apt-get install mdbtools&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sudo apt-get install mdbtools-gmdb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Then, click on Applications&amp;gt;Office&amp;gt;MDB Viewer.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In Ubuntu, mdbtools includes command line tools such as mdb-export and
mdb-schema and to export data from the MS Access .mdb files, extract contents
from each table from each .mdb file through the shell --for which one needs to
determine table names before using:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mdbtools &amp;lt;filename.mdb&amp;gt; &amp;lt;table name&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;output_filename.txt&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mdb-export filename.mdb tblfoo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
The compressed archice included among other things, files with .ocx and .tlb
extensions. More googling (yay!)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
TLB, a Visual Basic OLE Type Library, is a binary file containing all the type
information for using procedures or classes in DLLs.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
LINKS:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
o. &lt;a href=&quot;http://ubuntuforums.org/showthread.php?t=1120032&quot;&gt;mdb-tools and
postgresql script&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2010-10-11T17:58:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:md5:439a9a60e9c948c542c06425a5d0d734">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: Openhatch IRC meet</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2010/Openhatch-IRC-meet</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;On the Ubuntu-Women list we get a number of women introducing themselves,
listing their coding skills, wanting to contribute, etc.. Right now we simply
re-direct them to the specific communities within Ubuntu -- to find a project
to contribute they have to use keywords to search Launchpad.net for bugs....
search for &amp;quot;perl&amp;quot; / &amp;quot;python&amp;quot; packages, or search for a specific project of
choice and squash the bugs listed there -- this does not seem like a terribly
efficient way to track participation or contribute, besides being confusing
and/or intimidating for someone who is new to the community and is completely
un-aware of how floss communities work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before anyone says IRC, I should chime in that the infrastructure issues
(power outages, poor bandwidth, &lt;a href=&quot;http://svaksha.com/post/2010/the-Sparsh-BPO-s-Intelenet-way-to-gyp-BSNL&quot;&gt;poor tech support&lt;/a&gt;,
etc...) in India make it that much harder to contribute. This is not true for
other nations with superior basic (power, water, roads, etc..)
infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how do we know if a contributor actually searches and finds what she
wants to work on or is even comfortable working with? Does she leave because
the information she came looking for was not available and/or was simply
intimidated by the sheer size and vast technical scope within Ubuntu? These are
unanswered questions which I have wondered about -- not knowing if we managed
to retain a contributor is a grey area.&lt;/p&gt;
Existing members are volunteers themselves with responsibilities, making it
harder to track if we are losing technical contributions because we dont know
what happens after the initial guidance to a query on the list. I'd been
wondering how we could narrow the scope and find technical areas where UW can
collaborate with other Ubuntu teams needing help.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In essence that is the usecase: Suppose a woman lists &amp;quot;C/C++ and networking&amp;quot; or
&amp;quot;python and AI&amp;quot; as her skillsets, how could we scrape information from LP and
use it to channelize women to specific bugs that need squashing --the
difficulty level, its upstream/downstream, etc... Could we use an API for
data-mining LP for possible areas of interest and list these on our wiki-pages,
or post mails to the mailing list or push them into an RSS/Atom news feed on
&lt;a href=&quot;http://planet.ubuntu-women.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;planet.ubuntu-women.org&lt;/a&gt;, enabling interested folks to subscribe to
the news feed.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
After that I pinged Asheesh of &lt;a href=&quot;http://openhatch.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;openhatch&lt;/a&gt; which does something similar -- tags all the floss bug
trackers for open bugs, small bite-sized bugs and the big ones too. The idea
sounded interestin to him and he called for a meetup -- The meetup is on
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/converted.html?day=11&amp;amp;month=10&amp;amp;year=2010&amp;amp;hour=9&amp;amp;min=0&amp;amp;sec=0&amp;amp;p1=771&amp;amp;p2=263&quot;&gt;
Monday, Oct11 at 9am IST&lt;/a&gt; on #openhatch (logged) on irc.freenode.net and its
just meant to bounce off ideas iirc.&lt;br /&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2010-10-09T08:07:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:md5:cec481b5610dae08a4f908177f3109c4">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: Dojo-20101008</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2010/Dojo-20101008</link>
	<content:encoded>As per the schedule, we had the first dojo meet at CIS yesterday. Met Satish
Kumar while searching for the CIS office and a helpful biker who cursed
google-maps actually guided us there as we were both relying on the wrong
geo-location plots on Google-maps (openstreetmap someone?)...as if the city's
whimsical penchant for one-way roads was not irritating enough. There is an
interesting anecdote --the biker who guided us there took us to the exact
building and i asked him how he knew the place when 'CIS' didnt strike a memory
chord. He promptly replied that there was a foreigner (he used the term
'white') who worked at CIS whom he has seen around town. Ah! There is something
about finding your way around Indian roads, something to be said about the
human touch that google-maps or other tech gadgets cannot compete with.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The CIS staff were very helpful and Royson immediately arranged refreshments
and we both started off discussing what the dojo was all about -- many &lt;a href=&quot;http://svaksha.com/post/2010/weekly-python-dojo-meetups-in-bangalore&quot;&gt;dojo participants around
the world&lt;/a&gt; were nice enough to have a discussion on how they did things,
what worked and didnt -- so it being the first day we had time to discuss how
to structure it or not to have a structure at all, etc... In the middle of this
discussion NigelB and Akshay Gandhi walked in and the discussion veered to the
RHCE course he had joined. Later Nigel showed us the git graph he was working
on. We had a longish discussion on git, bug trackers, communities and it was
8.45pm when we left, but not before planning to meet next week to work on nltk
at 7pm same place. Join us!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I'm was multi-tasking --listening to a IE9 product pitch for html5/css3, while
typing this entry, so any errors and missing information can be attributed to
the much tortured greycells. &amp;lt;/excuse&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2010-10-09T05:05:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:md5:002216bc84d8cb91c3ec3d575cb49573">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: The Sparsh BPO's Intelenet way to gyp BSNL</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2010/The-Sparsh-BPO-s-Intelenet-way-to-gyp-BSNL</link>
	<content:encoded>I've been having DNS issues since last weekend and since my &lt;a href=&quot;http://bsnl.sparshindia.com/&quot;&gt;ISP has been happily outsourcing&lt;/a&gt; its
customer service obligations to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sparshindia.com&quot;&gt;Sparsh
India&lt;/a&gt;, so whenever the DNS conks off (which is once a month at the very
least), I get to have interesting conversations very often.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[after our initial conversation when I've tried explaining the DNS problem, in
vain.]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ME&lt;/strong&gt;: I've tried changing the DNS to point to 208.67.222.222,
saved and rebooted the router, etc... , can ping &amp;quot;random&amp;quot; server, can use IRC,
etc...BUT cannot connect to some websites like &amp;quot;www.zareason.com&amp;quot;, which gets
redirected to
&amp;quot;http://searchportal.information.com/?a_id=92438&amp;amp;domainname=www.zareason.com&amp;quot;.
Please reboot your DNS server as it does not resolve some domains
properly.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;CSR&lt;/strong&gt;: Click on 'start button', click on 'internet explorer',
...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;ME&lt;/strong&gt;: Excuse me ...Sir/M'am, I told you I dont have windows on
this machine. I use a Linux-based operating system so if you tell me what
information you require to troubleshoot, I can check for it locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At this point I'm put on hold, ...CSR returns after a few minutes to ask if I
can connect to 'google.com'. I answer in the affirmative and he/she proceeds to
say the problem is because I use Linux and there is nothing they can do about
it. Simply stunning.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Asking to speak to another person who knows &amp;quot;linux+networking&amp;quot; or a team leader
results in them disconnecting your call. That isnt surprising. A Business line
article says &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thehindubusinessline.com/2009/11/03/stories/2009110351370400.htm&quot;&gt;Sparsh
BPO, which is the domestic arm of Intelenet Global Services, put in a bid at Rs
1.15 a call for providing contact centre services....&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; -- The higher the
number of calls to the BSNL toll-free numbers will result in more income for
Sparsh. I'm not aware of the finer points in their SLA but the pattern I have
observed is very very common. Calls are always dropped, sometimes mid-way,
etc...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sparshindia.com/&quot;&gt;Sparshindia&lt;/a&gt; is a subsidiary of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.intelenetglobal.com/&quot;&gt;Intelenetglobal&lt;/a&gt;, meant to handle
the pan-India BPO business. I am curious to know if Intelenet provides similar
poor service to their US clients. Would a CSR disconnect an overseas call
mid-way without solving the customers problem? Will they get to bill clients
simply on the basis of number of calls handled without actually solving the
problem.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sparshindia.com/opration_quality.html&quot;&gt;http://www.sparshindia.com/opration_quality.html&lt;/a&gt;,
states they monitor calls and have a good QA process. I beg to differ. If I
call back and go through the whole discussion for the N'th time and insist on
speaking to a TL, I'll be put on hold, and the same person pretends to be
another person. Oh well, it takes more than changing voices and giving a fake
name -- the 'trying too hard to fake it' bit that gives them away. Nine out of
ten times the conversation has gone downhill when the CSR insists that you are
having a DNS issue because you are using Linux.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
https://www.zareason.com/  was also unable to connect and &lt;a href=&quot;http://svaksha.com/will%20want%20to%20save%20on%20bandwidth%20and&quot;&gt;dig
@8.8.8.8 zareason.com&lt;/a&gt; returns the correct IP address. While I grok that
every ISP out there uses a transparent proxy to save on bandwidth. Using an
anonymous proxy gives me the zareason website but what if its a site you want
to order something. How can the user know or trust the site if the ISP has
borked DNS which just redirects you to a phishing site?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
On multiple occasions I have requested to speak to any technical person who
understands &amp;quot;linux + networking&amp;quot; as the DNS issue has a simple solution --
Probably the DNS server used by the proxy is broken and its is caching
incorrect data. The backend technical team (whom i've spoken to just once in so
many years) can reboot the server and clear the cache. This is all it takes,
all of 5 minutes to reboot the appropriate server and solve the DNS issue. BUT
its easier to do a shirsasana (head-stand) than get the sparshindia agents to
reboot the darn dns server.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE&lt;/strong&gt;: I called Sparsh India yet again. This time I refused
all the request to give the mobile number so the outbound process would call
me. Erm...I would hold on forever until the DNS problem was solved. As of
writing this, its been 2 hours that i've been talking to a TL (he claimed so),
who finally booked my complaint which I checked here: '&lt;a href=&quot;http://bangaloretelecom.com/&quot;&gt;http://bangaloretelecom.com/&lt;/a&gt;' --it has no
details of the problem. The excuse this guy gives me is 'BSNL must have blocked
the site&amp;quot; ...hilarious, why would bsnl want to block one site peddling
computers? If it were a p0rn site that argument might atleast make sense. We
retraced the steps of changing the routers WAN settings and other tasks which
didnt help.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Which part of the sentence &amp;quot;I can access websites and surf online, only some
sites like zareason dont work, reboot your DNS server and solve the problem&amp;quot;
does a person not grok?  He even pretended to not know how to spell
&amp;quot;cache&amp;quot; and i could hear his co-worker giggle in the background. So I politely
told him that while he was busy 'pretending to not understand basic tech
terms', he was not harassing me, rather, he came across as a dumb person with
zero technical knowledge. That got his attention real quick and he didnt seem
to enjoy harassing me anymore. Oh, the joys of being a sexist troll !!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At the moment it seems that Sparsh India is only interested in increasing their
revenue by billing BSNL INR1.15 for each call that customers make --Not solving
the problem in one phone call definitely helps Sparsh and Intelenet gain more
revenue. Rebooting the server means the problem gets solved, hence less
revenue.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2010-10-05T06:42:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:md5:6b413b825604052a6b0557e32eea6d1e">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: Weekly Python dojos in Bangalore</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2010/Weekly-Python-dojos-in-Bangalore</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In an irc discussion this week, I suggested we kick-start a weekly &lt;a href=&quot;http://dojorio.wordpress.com/about/&quot;&gt;python-dojo&lt;/a&gt; meet-up in Bangalore.
Sunil Abraham of CIS was kind enough to donate their office space and even
offered to sponsor the java (pun unintended). Thanks Sunil/CIS.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So here's the plan for weekly python-dojo sessions in Bangalore,&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;WHAT&lt;/strong&gt;: Weekly python-dojo sessions in Bangalore which is
inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;http://dojorio.wordpress.com/about/&quot;&gt;dojorio&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://translate.google.com/translate?hl=en&amp;amp;sl=pt&amp;amp;u=http://dojorio.wordpress.com/&amp;amp;ei=z7GyS7OtCIvYsgOAvqTMBA&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;oi=translate&amp;amp;ct=result&amp;amp;resnum=1&amp;amp;ved=0CBQQ7gEwAA&amp;amp;prev=/search%3Fq%3Ddojorio%26hl%3Den%26prmd%3Dv&quot;&gt;english
translation&lt;/a&gt;) meetups in Brazil where they apply the &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://smallactsmanifesto.org/&quot;&gt;small acts manifesto&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;. The idea is to
create a friendly atmosphere which encourages &amp;quot;beginners&amp;quot; (...and experts and
everyone in between) to share and learn with the community. Please bring your
laptops/netbooks etc.. as the dojo will be hands-on where we will work on small
problems that exist in FLOSS software which automatically helps us learn a lot
more about our system. Folks that dont have laptops are also welcome -- atm, we
cant provide machines to work on but you can watch others, ask questions,
learn, and later try it out at home.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;WHO&lt;/strong&gt; can participate: ANYONE. Absolutely anyone can walk in and
participate at the venue. There is no registration fee or cost (except your
time and travel costs perhaps?). There is no agenda either -- please note that
the environment would be similar to that of an unconference. There is no formal
teaching involved. We are all learners here and you are free to ask any
python-related question.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;WHERE&lt;/strong&gt;: The &lt;a href=&quot;http://cis-india.org/about&quot;&gt;Centre for
Internet and Society&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;amp;source=s_q&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;geocode=&amp;amp;q=CIS-INDIA+Bangalore+560+071&amp;amp;sll=12.965029,77.637269&amp;amp;sspn=0.005792,0.011362&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;hq=&amp;amp;hnear=Centre+for+Internet+and+Society+%28CIS%29,+2nd+Cross,+Bengaluru,+Karnataka+560071,+India&amp;amp;ll=12.964977,77.638772&amp;amp;spn=0.005792,0.011362&amp;amp;z=17&quot;&gt;google
map link&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;
No. 194, 2nd 'C' Cross, Domlur 2nd Stage, Bangalore 560 071&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;WHEN&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;span&gt;7pm-8pm every Friday&lt;/span&gt;.
We start from next week, &lt;strong&gt;08Oct2010&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So if you are interested in python, dont hesitate to join us for the weekly
dojo sessions and do spread the word -- dent/tweet, blog and mail your friends
about the weekly dojo meetups.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;PS&lt;/strong&gt;: If anyone (women in particular) feels the evening timings
are rather late for traveling please feel free to suggest a more convenient day
(sat/sun?) and time &amp;lt;-- its not set in stone and suggestions are
welcome.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2010-09-30T05:05:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:md5:821e032eba8eb0c6056d3ff0421ff3b2">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: PyConIndia-2010</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2010/day-one-at-INpycon2010</link>
	<content:encoded>Kinda sad to see all the effort put into a complete community volunteer-driven
event almost come to a standstill under the shadow of local communal politics
-- the Ayodhya verdict. Given that I missed last years even for personal
reasons, it seemed the Ayodhya verdict would be the roadblock this year.
Not.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Today, &lt;a href=&quot;http://in.pycon.org/2010/&quot;&gt;David Goodger kicked off the second
Pycon-India 2010&lt;/a&gt; in Bangalore with his keynote speech while briefly
dwelling on his Indian 'adventure' -- no seat-belts in the autorickshaw!? The
auditorium hall echoed with laughter!  Then it was a &lt;a href=&quot;http://in.pycon.org/2010/schedule&quot;&gt;series of talks&lt;/a&gt; on python 2to3,
multicore programming, and many more talks .... The only irritating part during
one talk was one audience member interrupting the speaker to discuss the
topic/ask questions. Probably this resulted in the speaker not getting enough
time to finish his talk and demo the code completely. In a 30-min talk it would
be a lot nicer if the audience restricted their questions to the last few
minutes *after* the speaker completes the talk.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Another interesting talk was the screen scraping talk but I'll return to my
lazyshell under the pretext that the videos will probably be uploaded online in
a few days. Else, you could just attend the second day of pycon coz the nicest
part was good 'ol networking, old friends, meeting new ones and the barcamp
style corridor chats with people. Considering that the attendees were almost
500+, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/mailman/listinfo/inpycon&quot;&gt;inpycon
team&lt;/a&gt; really pulled off a community event quite successfully! Now I gotta
get some sleep if I need to make it for tomorrows event!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2010-09-25T15:40:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:md5:5ec8805a2a1fc20c5c3ff35979412bd7">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: Call for proposals - PyCon 2011</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2010/Call-for-proposals-PyCon-2011</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;h3&gt;Call for proposals -- PyCon 2011 --
&lt;a href=&quot;http://us.pycon.org/2011/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://us.pycon.org/2011/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proposal Due date: November 1st, 2010&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
PyCon is back! With a rocking new website, a great location and more Python
hackers and luminaries under one roof than you could possibly shake a stick at.
We've also added an &amp;quot;Extreme&amp;quot; talk track this year - no introduction, no fluff
- only the pure technical meat!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
PyCon 2011 will be held March 9th through the 17th, 2011 in Atlanta, Georgia.
(Home of some of the best southern food you can possibly find on Earth!) The
PyCon conference days will be March 11-13, preceded by two tutorial days (March
9-10), and followed by four days of development sprints (March 14-17).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
PyCon 2011 is looking for proposals for the formal presentation tracks (this
includes &amp;quot;extreme talks&amp;quot;). A request for proposals for poster sessions and
tutorials will come separately.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Want to showcase your skills as a Python Hacker? Want to have hundreds of
people see your talk on the subject of your choice? Have some hot button issue
you think the community needs to address, or have some package, code or project
you simply love talking about? Want to launch your master plan to take over the
world with Python?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
PyCon is your platform for getting the word out and teaching something new to
hundreds of people, face to face.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In the past, PyCon has had a broad range of presentations, from reports on
academic and commercial projects, tutorials on a broad range of subjects, and
case studies. All conference speakers are volunteers and come from a myriad of
backgrounds: some are new speakers, some have been speaking for years. Everyone
is welcome, so bring your passion and your code! We've had some incredible past
PyCons, and we're looking to you to help us top them!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Online proposal submission is open now! Proposals  will be accepted
through November 10th, with acceptance notifications coming out by January
20th. To get started, please see:    &amp;lt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://us.pycon.org/2011/speaker/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://us.pycon.org/2011/speaker/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For videos of talks from previous years - check out:   &amp;lt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://python.mirocommunity.org/category/conferences&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://python.mirocommunity.org/category/conferences&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For more information on &amp;quot;Extreme Talks&amp;quot; see:   &amp;lt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://us.pycon.org/2011/speaker/extreme/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://us.pycon.org/2011/speaker/extreme/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We look forward to seeing you in Atlanta!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Please also note - registration for PyCon 2011 will also be capped at a maximum
of 1,500 delegates, including speakers. When registration opens (soon), you're
going to want to make sure you register early! Speakers with accepted talks
will have a guaranteed slot.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Important Dates:&lt;br /&gt;
  * November 1st, 2010: Talk proposals due.&lt;br /&gt;
  * December 15th, 2010: Acceptance emails sent.&lt;br /&gt;
  * January 19th, 2010: Early bird registration closes.&lt;br /&gt;
  * March 9-10th, 2011: Tutorial days at PyCon.&lt;br /&gt;
  * March 11-13th, 2011: PyCon main conference.&lt;br /&gt;
  * March 14-17th, 2011: PyCon sprints days.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Contact Emails:&lt;br /&gt;
  Van Lindberg (Conference Chair) - &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:van@python.org&quot;&gt;van@python.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  Jesse Noller (Co-Chair) - &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jnoller@python.org&quot;&gt;jnoller@python.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  PyCon Organizers list: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:pycon-organizers@python.org&quot;&gt;pycon-organizers@python.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2010-09-24T02:56:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4752247183054428289.post-7644676723622088348">
	<title>YAB: Yet Another Blog: Importance of being (Computer)Earnest</title>
	<link>http://thisisyab.blogspot.com/2010/09/importance-of-being-computerearnest.html</link>
	<content:encoded>Now its been more than 2yrs since i posted something on this blog and sometime since i blogged, so to say I've forgotten how to write may not be too much off the mark, not that I knew how to write/blog in first place! :)&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Well the ground-moving event that made me blog is something that happened today, that made me thankful for the first time for being a slightly knowledgeable person about computers. :)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The ubiquitous net decided to make a rare disappearing act today morning. And I had somehow associated such things to happen only in Third World countries, where I had lived all my life and to find such a thing happening in the First World was very surprising indeed! It got more surprising when i saw that Skype alone seemed to work, when all else was failing. That led me to conclude the problem was with BT's DNS servers. After the quick diagnosis, i knew i could vpn and use company's DNS servers and get connected to the net. So i get the vpn ip address from colleague via 'Skype - The Life Savior!' but for some reason my ipsec vpn decides to stop working then! :( So there i was still without connection to net. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Then /me thinks, this is 1st world after all, BT customer care should resolve this soon enough, so I get google IP from colleague, search for the BT customer support number and give them a call. And then i go through the longest call I've ever been put on hold - a record 30mins! even ICICIBank never did that to me back home! Well anyways as expected the call didn't yield much results, i was told many others are also seeing the same problem and it would be resolved in 24Hrs!  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;So i was back to square one. Then i ping another colleague, get the DNS server's ip directly, which i put in resolv.conf and lo internet works again! Its a wonderful feeling when you know only you have the net working when others don't just because you happen to have slightly more computer knowledge than the normal people. My Doctor hubby was suitably impressed when he couldn't connect to net from his laptop, when i could from mine. :D&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Anyways that led me to start wondering why we don't have a on-disk DNS cache. I know its a very remote chance of my kind of scenario happening, plus it doesn't make any sense for mobile users, where the nearest DNS keeps changing. But for a home-desktop user wouldn't this make sense? Imagine if there was some option to cache the most used DNS entries, I wouldn't even have noticed that net was down. And by the way thats what happened with my iPhone, where i could access gmail, facebook everything, as it was using the cached DNS resolutions to connect.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;So thats about it, until another such ground-moving event happens,&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Adios &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;:P&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/4752247183054428289-7644676723622088348?l=thisisyab.blogspot.com&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2010-09-21T19:43:09+00:00</dc:date>
	<dc:creator>Puthali</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4752247183054428289.post-2557162170420241408">
	<title>YAB: Yet Another Blog: Easy!</title>
	<link>http://thisisyab.blogspot.com/2008/06/easy.html</link>
	<content:encoded>He he, this basically nullifies my previous post. :)&lt;br /&gt;Slam No. 4 for Rafa and man did he make it look like a cake walk! :D&lt;br /&gt;Before the start of the match i was feeling sad that i wouldn't be able to watch the entire match as i had to attend 10 'o clock show of '21' @ Inox. But then quickly realized i didn't have any cause for it. Thanks to Rafa, no its more thanks to Federer for finishing it in just 108 minutes. :) So all those people who were just waiting to proclaim Federer as the greatest ever, wait for one more year at least, if not forever... :P&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;'21' was not as good as i thought it would be. Come on you can depict Vegas much better than that! .  And you can so do away with all that hollywoodization, the cliched 'best friends ignored' track, soppy romantic track, jealousy...i mean why introduce a 5-10min plot line just for heck of it?  Well don't mind, it was quite an enjoyable movie, but the problem for me was that there was no freshness about it,  apart from the basic plot.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As result of watching '21', i missed F1 :(  I reached home just when press conference had started and to see Kubica, Heidfield and Coultard was shocking to say the least. I did see the pit-lane mishap recap but somehow can't help feeling that i missed out on some good live action.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;'n yea, now Germany beat Poland. :)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On a side-note i finally managed to read 'Hobbit' today. :) The decision to read it was rekindled by the LOTR dvds 've been watching these days. Its this boxed set, with 4 dvd's per each part so 12 in all. Any serious LoTR fan should possess this. :)&lt;br /&gt;The making i.e the Appendices part though long(2 dvds per each part) is amazing. While watching that today morning, my Dad remarked if i was planning to go into film-making and man do i wish that i was part of it! :)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Anyways sleep beckons,&lt;br /&gt;Adios&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/4752247183054428289-2557162170420241408?l=thisisyab.blogspot.com&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2010-09-21T18:36:28+00:00</dc:date>
	<dc:creator>Puthali</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://barkha.in/blog/?p=141">
	<title>Certified crazy: Where have I been?</title>
	<link>http://barkha.in/blog/2010/09/20/where-have-i-been/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In the Kitchen, ofcourse!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last few weeks, I have been either busy with work, or cooking in the kitchen, and trying out new things. Among the recent experiments during the past two weeks are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cheese and Macaroni (and veggies!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strawberry tartelettes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stuffed colorful bell peppers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fleur de courgette (zucchini flowers)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to go to the marché provençal in Antibes to do the regular fresh vegetable shopping instead of the normal weekend trip to the Carrefour supermarket. It was a refreshing change &amp;#8211; seemed like I am back in the bhaji market of Malad (w) with Maa &amp;#8211; only all the haggling was in french &lt;img src=&quot;http://barkha.in/blog/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; class=&quot;wp-smiley&quot; /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first tasted the fleur de courgette at a french home last week &amp;#8211; I became instant fan of the dish and tried to reverse engineer the dish &amp;#8211; almost there, but something is still missing. This doesnt let me down &amp;#8211; I am going to try again next Sunday and see if I can remake it the way I first tasted it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May be, inspired by Runa&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://mishti.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;cooking blog,&lt;/a&gt; I should start my own instead of twitpic-ing the pictures? Let us see.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2010-09-20T13:16:49+00:00</dc:date>
	<dc:creator>barkha</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:md5:c05cf2cca24cf1424a6dd33c6b139090">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: gnome outreach program for women - 2010 internships</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2010/gnome-outreach-program-for-women-2010-internships</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The application process for the first round of internships sponsored by the
GNOME Foundation are now officially open. The dates for these internships are
&lt;strong&gt;2010Dec15 to 2011Mar15&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any &lt;strong&gt;woman&lt;/strong&gt; who has relevant experience and is available for
a full-time internship is welcome to apply. The application deadline is
&lt;strong&gt;2010Oct25.&lt;/strong&gt; As part of the application process, they are asking
women to take the time to learn about the participating projects and make a
contribution to the one they are interested in. These projects include ones in
programming, graphic design, documentation, and marketing. For more program
details, visit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://live.gnome.org/GnomeWomen/OutreachProgram2010&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://live.gnome.org/GnomeWomen/OutreachProgram2010&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Do consider applying for the internship, signing up as a mentor, or helping
spread the word by encouraging woman to apply - Blog, email, dent/tweet or
&lt;a href=&quot;http://live.gnome.org/GnomeWomen/OutreachProgram2010?action=AttachFile&amp;amp;do=view&amp;amp;target=gnome-women-outreach-poster.png&quot;&gt;
download this flyer&lt;/a&gt; (designed by Máirín Duffy) to send the information
about this internship program to your local school/college/university or hand
it out at conferences. All the materials for spreading the word are here:
&lt;a href=&quot;http://live.gnome.org/GnomeWomen/OutreachProgram2010/SpreadTheWord&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://live.gnome.org/GnomeWomen/OutreachProgram2010/SpreadTheWord&lt;/a&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2010-09-18T05:34:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:md5:ae30cc0f093f7c7d86f3297397e0bfba">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: ilug bengaluru meetup today</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2010/ilug-bengaluru-meetup-today</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ILUG Bengaluru Meetup on Saturday 2010Sep18&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;:  1800 - 1930 hrs&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Venue&lt;/strong&gt;:  Jaaga,  Rhenius Street (Off. Richmond Road)
, Opposite Hockey Stadium, Shantinagar, Bangalore&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Directions&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://jaaga.in/contact&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://jaaga.in/contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Agenda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Open house:        Anything goes barcamp-ish session.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Regular Activities:         GPG keysigning - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/events/keysigning&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.debian.org/events/keysigning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;:  This is a back-to-back meetup with Ubuntu-IN . The
Ubuntu-IN meetup is from 1630 to 1800hrs and is about Indian Language
Localisation and all other things Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2010-09-18T05:14:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:md5:49c70145804456c1bf9071abcb233108">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: postgresql packaging bug in lucid</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2010/postgresql-packaging-bug-in-lucid</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Postgresql-8.4 is the packaged version for Ubuntu 10.04 (aka lucid) but
earlier today I purged and reinstalled it and found a packaging bug --
&lt;code&gt;sudo aptitude purge postgresql&lt;/code&gt; does not cleanly remove the conf
files from the filesystem if they had been edited. All the older edits I had
made to &lt;code&gt;/etc/postgresql/8.4/main/pg_hba.conf&lt;/code&gt; and
&lt;code&gt;/etc/postgresql/8.4/main/pg_ident.conf&lt;/code&gt; files were intact after the
reinstallation. So the new re-installation would throw weird errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally aptitude/apt-get 'purge' is the cleanest way to uninstall software
but if you have customized the configuration settings in a DB you would not
like to lose those changes (especially because you may have installed the
database a long time ago and may not remember each change for different apps
that use the DB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds good but in theory a 'purge' littering your filesystem with edited
files makes it hard for folks to hunt out which file was leftover and whether
re-editing &amp;quot;foo.conf&amp;quot; would get &amp;quot;foo-application&amp;quot; running smoothly.  For
smaller single packages its probably easy to script a list of files from the
original package and check the filesystem against that list but what if you had
an installation that had 80+ odd installation steps for multiple packages that
depend on each other ...that is a lot of retracing -- the installation and
purging of 80+ installation steps is scriptable but a clean reinstallation of
your OS is far less time-consuming, not to mention the resource savings.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2010-09-08T17:35:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:md5:248fc1e5da5cc217b4a39175730aea0c">
	<title>॥ स्वक्ष ॥ svaksha: seeking indian university volunteers to contribute code to kde-koffice</title>
	<link>http://svaksha.com/post/2010/seeking-indian-university-volunteers-to-contribute-code-to-koffice</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This post makes it after a long latency period that I'm not proud of.
Apologies Boudewijn!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boudewijn Rempt, CTO of &lt;a href=&quot;http://kogmbh.com&quot;&gt;KO GmbH&lt;/a&gt;, a company
that works on open source projects around &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.koffice.org&quot;&gt;KOffice&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oasis-open.org/committees/tc_home.php?wg_abbrev=office&quot;&gt;OpenDocument&lt;/a&gt;
and Qt is looking for Indian university contacts for establishing project
channels to increase volunteer contribution to Free/Libre software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Europe, he has been a mentor of a student who did his MA Thesis on
writing brush engines and algorithms for Krita and had visited India in May to
give a training to some university students who were going to do an internship
with Nokia, working on KOffice. A large part of that training was about getting
involved with a free software project and he would like the opportunity to do
the same for other groups of students and would love to work together with
people to set up similar projects at Indian colleges, universities and with
companies because when students do their internship or thesis in cooperation
with a free software project, they will learn a lot that is really
valuable: working together with teams, producing software that has end users,
working with large, real-life code bases and the projects might gain long term
contributors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Boudewijn, KOffice is C++ based --only some applications can be
scripted in Python and they use some Python scripts for things like quality
control, but the apps and libraries are C++. You can read the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.koffice.org/index.php?title=Building/Building_KOffice&quot;&gt;detailed
build instructions&lt;/a&gt; and if it interests you then directly contact Boudewijn
Rempt at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:boud@valdyas.org&quot;&gt;boud@valdyas.org&lt;/a&gt; (private) OR
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:boud@kogmbh.com&quot;&gt;boud@kogmbh.com&lt;/a&gt; (company address).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: Feel free to circulate this widely to all Indian universities and
colleges as FLOSS is meant for everyone/anyone interested in learning something
new.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2010-09-07T10:25:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="urn:lj:livejournal.com:atom1:kadambarid:81472">
	<title>kadambarid: Of rains and other such precipitation ...</title>
	<link>http://kadambarid.livejournal.com/81472.html</link>
	<content:encoded>I remember reading this lovely book about a man whose quest was to follow the course of the monsoon in India. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Chasing-Monsoon-Modern-Pilgrimage-Through/dp/0805020527&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Chasing the Monsoon&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;i&gt;Alexander Frater&lt;/i&gt;. He starts in Kerala at the advent of the monsoon and &quot;chases&quot; it just short of the &lt;i&gt;Seven Sisters&lt;/i&gt; (the North-East of India, for those of you weak on &lt;i&gt;sobriquets&lt;/i&gt;). This was a few years ago, by which time I had developed a plethora of &quot;rainy-day fantasies&quot;. Some of them have come true and some others, repeatedly so. Sit by the window sill, either at a table near the window or on a bed suitably arranged (this of course requires appropriate foresight when getting the house furnished, but that's another tale), leaning against a big bolster (if applicable to the seating), sipping deliciously warm lemon tea or cocoa (this was before my obsession with herbal teas of all consistencies and colors), and reading a book. Nothing even comes close to this feeling. This fantasy would of course get better - simply intersperse the reading with moments of thoughtfulness (or thoughtlessness, as the case may be), staring into the rain as though it were the object of your doctoral thesis, and not to forget absentmindedly biting into crisp, hot &lt;i&gt;pakoras&lt;/i&gt;. There would be variations of this fantasy - involving fireplaces and rugs and what not, for the curious amongst you, but we'll not be covering them just as yet. The mood and setting just perfect for some &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Simon_%26_Garfunkel&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Simon&amp;amp;Garfunkel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;i&gt;vasantha&lt;/i&gt; or &lt;i&gt;amruthavarshini&lt;/i&gt;.  And, although I'm a great lover of science-fiction - this fantasy requires something more attuned to the situation. Like M&amp;amp;Bs (oh, c'mon - don't be judgemental!), Wodehouse, Gerald Durrell, Dave Barry or James Herriot. Terry Pratchett or Douglas Adams could be squeezed in perhaps, but trust me, nothing beats some &lt;i&gt;romance&lt;/i&gt;/&lt;i&gt;humor&lt;/i&gt;. And then, there are those books that do NOT depend on the weather (even if their titles mention something related) - no one would want to day-dream and sit around enjoying some atmospheric phenomenon after reading &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Everybody-Loves-Good-Drought-Districts/dp/0747276161&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Everybody Loves a Good Drought&lt;/a&gt;. The reader has to be one cold person to not feel like doing something useful! I was inspired enough to seriously consider following P.Sainath's footsteps and pursue &quot;his&quot; kind of journalism ... but we're digressing and that's another rainy-day story (old-and-now-obsolete pun)! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Another fantasy that had caught my fancy was of course actually &lt;i&gt;doing&lt;/i&gt; what Alexander Frater did, and follow his wet (pun unintended) trail. I will maybe do that. Sometime. I do have a knack for arriving at the worst possible weather in many places. Take the past year alone - I traveled by sleeper class train from Madras to Delhi during the height of summer, reached Bombay from Madras when the monsoon was bent on impressing me with &quot;quantity&quot;, landed in Chicago in peak winter (when I'd never in my life seen sub-zero) and got back to Bombay in time for yet-another-monsoon. And oh, I also managed to visit Seattle during it's &quot;rainy season&quot; (so to speak) and Texas in summer. It has been very, very interesting and a lot of fun. I somehow don't remember spending too much time gazing out of glass panes, enjoying the snow. It was nice, especially walking during a snow-fall (read snow-FALL, not storm, or blizzard), covered from head to toe, holding hands with your loved one, listening to the almost silent falling of the flakes, and feeling them gently plop on your face ... but I somehow never got to watching the snow flakes, reading, and all that jazz. On the other hand, I truly don't enjoy walking (or doing anything even remotely outdoorsy) during a downpour. Nope, that's not for me. Especially in India. It quite nice walking in a drizzle, but not when it's raining cats-and-dogs. I remember how I'd have my raincoat on AND an umbrella to go anywhere - it's not as much fun as watching from the other side of a window! And driving/riding are not much better, but that's just because of the &lt;strike&gt;roads&lt;/strike&gt; potholes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have also had a lot of fun in the rain. There's NOTHING like playing football when it's pouring. At least, that was the case for me at the age of 13. And, if you're in Bombay during the rains, it sacrilegious to not go on a &lt;i&gt;monsoon trek&lt;/i&gt;. There are places in Bombay or minutes from it that are fantastic to hike/trek. Moreover, there are hundreds of forts that could be covered in these monsoon hikes, for those looking for a taste of history. There are an incredible number of trekking outfits that go weekend after weekend. For the more adventurous amongst you (yeah, that's you, the person enjoying adding buckets of water to torrential rain),  I would recommend &lt;i&gt;waterfall rappelling&lt;/i&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abseiling&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;abseiling&lt;/a&gt;. Here are a few photos of me, taken during a recent waterfall rappelling trip to a place near &lt;i&gt;Bhivpuri&lt;/i&gt;, some 80 km from Mumbai. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000fxh4q/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000fxh4q/s320x240&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000fy3f3/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://pics.livejournal.com/kadambarid/pic/000fy3f3/s320x240&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;238&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The falls were about 60 ft high, and considered amongst the easier to rappel. It was my first time waterfall rappelling, although I have done some rock-climbing and certain other erm, drier-forms of rappelling. It was not really that easy and I slipped and dinged myself against the rocks more than once, until I realized the key was &quot;technique, technique, technique&quot;. You need to be at right angles to the wall, legs wide, taking small steps backward with the help of ropes that involve use of both hands. And oh, tip backwards but don't go overboard (pun unintended) - you'll just topple backwards! AND, keep a distance between the feet - bring them close and you'll start oscillating like a pendulum! Instructions such as these are a mouthful for an amateur to handle, but after learning to pick myself up after my first, nasty fall, there was, the proverbial, no going back. But mind you, it was darn exhilarating. You can take your time going down (it's not as bad as it sounds!), and stop and relish the view from midair. As your near the bottom, the head-rush and adrenalin-high are unmistakeable. The safety measures were in place and at no point did I feel really vulnerable or precarious. Very, very importantly: they didn't make anyone sign a form saying &quot;We're not responsible for accidental death or damage, blah, blah blah...&quot; or something along those lines, and THAT was a huge relief. To start something after signing stuff like that IS scary and darn weird!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Again, I just meandered off! I started typing this listening to the rain, and decided to write (for a change, rather than read). There were also some personal storms raging, and simply sitting and writing brought about a relaxing lull. As you can now surmise, I like the rains. Over the years, I have also learnt to accept and enjoy summer and winter and monsoon, sunshine and snowflakes and everything in between. I guess that's the way it is - everyone will enjoy the rain, as long as they're not hurrying for an appointment, trying desperately to catch an auto, dressed just seconds ago in crisp white!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And, on that philosophical note ...</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2010-09-01T21:46:03+00:00</dc:date>
</item>

</rdf:RDF>
